<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-04-27T19:49:35-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/</id>
<title>Manifest Life</title>
<entry>
<title>Krispy Kreme - Case Study</title>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Krispy-Kreme-Casen-Study/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Krispy Kreme - Case Study" />
<published>2016-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
<updated>2016-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Krispy-Kreme-Casen-Study</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Krispy-Kreme-Casen-Study/">&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme Case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robyn Crean, Jason DiCarlo, Amy Granville, Isaiah King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lasell College&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Company Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme Doughnuts was created when Vernon Rudolph discovered an old
hand-written doughnut recipe that his uncle, a Kentucky farmer, had
purchased in 1933. Today, Krispy Kreme Doughnuts, Inc. is an iconic
international &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doughnut&quot;&gt;doughnut&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_coffeehouse_chains&quot;&gt;coffeehouse
chain&lt;/a&gt; using
the same secret recipe that Rudolph’s uncle purchased in New Orleans,
currently locked up in a safe in Winston-Salem.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In the beginning,
Krispy Kreme was solely a wholesale bakery baking doughnuts for local
grocery stores. However, the local residents couldn’t get enough of the
intoxicating aroma from the factory leading Rudolph to the decision of
selling directly to the community. Rudolph ordered, “Cut a hole in the
factory wall and sell ’em out on to the street.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the 1950’s Krispy Kreme became a regional chain with thirty shops
located throughout the Southeast. After Rudolph’s death in 1973, Krispy
Kreme was sold to Beatrice Foods who ultimately led the company
downhill. The relationship between Beatrice Foods and Krispy Kreme has
been described as “a bad marriage” by former CEO, Scott Livengood.
Livengood also stated, “Beatrice didn’t care so much if the stores made
money, as long as we sold doughnuts to supermarkets. She didn’t want to
invest in stores or expand the company.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1982 a group of twenty-two franchises joined together and purchased
Krispy Kreme in a leveraged buyout. The company now in the hands of
individuals who cared about the brand implemented a new innovative
marketing effort to re-vamp the brand. The concept of the “Doughnut
Theater” was then born. This idea allowed customers to watch the entire
doughnut making process right in the store. Other efforts to help entice
business include “Hot Doughnut Now” signs, which were placed in every
retail branch. These signs were lit to notify consumers whenever fresh
doughnuts were finished baking. Customers could then walk in and receive
a free glazed doughnut.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after, Krispy Kreme was experiencing rapid expansion. By the end of
1999, Krispy Kreme had 144 shops in 27 states and revenues climbing to
$220 million. In April 2000, Krispy Kreme became a publicly traded
company.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In December of the following year, Krispy Kreme opened a
store in Toronto, Canada; one of 49 stores added that year. Due to
exponential growth rates in May 2004, many sales became flat leading
Krispy Kreme to experience their first unprofitable quarter. With this
negative outcome and other issues within the company, Krispy Kreme’s
long-time CEO Scott Livengood stepped down and was replaced by Stephen
Copper. Hoping that he could turn things around, Cooper began the
recovery process. However, this proved to be too much for him to handle
because shortly after he handed the reins over to Daryl Brewster.
Brewster’s turnaround strategy called for Krispy Kreme to cut costs at a
sustainable level to prevent bankruptcy as well as adapting to the
health-conscious consumer and expanding internationally. Krispy Kreme
continued to struggle, even with Brewster’s strategy in place. Soon
after, James Morgan took over the business. Under Morgan’s leadership
the company had its first consecutive profitable years in 2010-2011
since the firm reached its peak in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012 Krispy Kreme celebrated its 75^th^ anniversary of selling “Melt
in Your Mouth Joy” doughnuts. On June 1, 2014 Tony Thompson was
appointed President and CEO of Krispy Kreme.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Most recently, Krispy
Kreme opened its 1,000^th^ store in Kansas City. Krispy Kreme has
implemented many innovative ideas in efforts to keep the company
relevant. The company has also introduced new healthier menu items such
as oatmeal, yogurt, and juice at select locations. The company also
offers a smaller, “bit sized” doughnut as well as a whole wheat doughnut
option as healthier alternatives. They have also introduced a variety of
coffee, crullers, seasonal/holiday-inspired doughnuts, ice cream and
doughnut sundaes, and a line of “chillers” which are Krispy Kreme’s
version of a smoothie and doughnut milk shakes. Although there are
numerous flavors of doughnuts, mini doughnuts, and doughnut holes, the
Original Glazed has always been the most popular product sold by the
company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By experimenting with different markets to delve into, the company has
managed to stay relevant and create new revenue streams. Krispy Kreme
also created a prominent presence abroad which has proven to be very
important to the company. Though the company has had its ups and downs,
Krispy Kreme will always maintain a role as one of the leading doughnut
brands in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;General Environmental Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Political Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme must adhere to many different codes including: Code of
Business Conduct and Ethics, Code of Ethics for Chief Executive and
Senior Financial Officers, Chief Executive Officer Succession Policy,
Corporate Governance Guidelines, Policy and Procedure with Respect to
Related Person Transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Code of Business Conduct and Ethics is a code of conduct which is
a set of organizational rules regarding values, beliefs, ethics, and
matters of legal compliance. Organizational members are responsible for
adhering to the code of conduct and will be held accountable for failure
to do so.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Codes of conduct prohibit behavior and inform employees of
what is expected of them. Also outlined in the code are penalties for
failure to comply. A few common topics in Business Codes that arise are:
Conflicts of interest, Confidential information, Employment
discrimination, Use of the organization’s property, Financial reporting
and accounting, Health and safety issues, Political contributions and
campaigning in the office, and Legal compliance issues relevant to the
organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Code of Ethics for Chief Executive and Senior Financial Officers is
similar to the Code of Business Conduct and Ethics, however the Chief
Executive Officer and senior financial officers are subjected to
additional policies. One rule states, The CEO and each senior financial
officer shall promptly bring to the attention of the General Counsel any
information he or she may have concerning alleged evidence of a material
violation of the securities or other laws, rules or regulations
applicable to the Company and the operation of its business, by the
Company or any agent thereof, or of a material violation of the Code of
Business Ethics or of these additional procedures.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is the Chief Executive Officer Succession Policy. This policy is a
guideline to a change in executive leadership in a company. Krispy Kreme
has created a plan to insure stability and accountability of the company
in preparation for a planned or unplanned change in leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Corporate Governance Guidelines provide a framework for the
governance of Krispy Kreme. Corporate governance involves balancing the
interests of shareholders, management, customers, suppliers, financiers,
government and the community. Not only does it provide a framework for
attaining objectives but it also covers every area of management.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme has quite a few government regulations to stay compliant
to, including local regulation. Their stores are subject to licensing
through government authorities such as health, sanitation, safety, and
fire agencies. In order to meet these regulations, they must respect
zoning, land use, and environmental factors. Another regulation that
must be met is the food product regulation. Krispy Kreme must meet all
federal state and governmental rules. “For example, the ingredient list,
product weight and other aspects of our product labels are subject to
state and federal regulation for accuracy and content. Most states
periodically check products for compliance. The use of various product
ingredients and packaging materials is regulated by the United States
Department of Agriculture and the Federal Food and Drug Administration.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few other political factors that affect the success of Krispy
Kreme. One political interference would be the minimum wage and
employment law changes. Most of the Krispy Kreme employees and staff are
usually individuals with little experience or education. Although the
company does take time to train these individuals, they are usually paid
minimum wage. Therefore, Krispy Kreme is affected by the minimum wage
increases.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More political factors that affect the company are the government
efforts to reduce the risks of obesity. Although it is highly doubtful
that the government will enforce laws banning high fat and unhealthy
food options, the possibility still exists.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Economic Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the rise and fall of the economy, consumer spending has
tightened. Where customers are more critical about where they spend
their money, Krispy Kreme has been affected by selling a product that is
considered to be a non-essential food item. Therefore, the company may
feel a pressure in sales. Due to limited customer spending, the fight
for sales against competitors has intensified.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other economical factors affecting the business would be the rise of
wheat and soybean oil prices. These are key ingredients in Krispy Kreme
doughnuts which have reached record high prices.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:13&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Also, Krispy Kreme
is taking a big hit from return rates from the company’s wholesale
partners whose rate are higher than normal. One of the biggest issues
affecting the economic achievement of Krispy Kreme is their overuse of
discounted promotions. Although these promotions entice numerous
consumers to purchase doughnuts or other products, the cut in costs from
the many promotions are actually hindering the success of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are a few negative economic factors, there are some
positive. Krispy Kreme is able to purchase key supplies at volume
discount prices that competitors may not be receiving. Krispy Kreme is
very selective in choosing suppliers and requires potential suppliers to
meet certain standards in regards to quality and reliability. The
economy overall is not a prominent factor determining Krispy Kreme’s
success because they are not affected by the gross domestic product
indicators or unemployment numbers unlike most companies.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:14&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sociological Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge sociological factor affects the success of Krispy Kreme would be
the awareness and concern about health and ingredients in food. Where
consumers are becoming more aware and cautious about what they are
putting in their bodies, they have become more critical about where they
spend their money to purchase food items. Due to outbursts across the
world of boycotting trans fats and other ingredients, Krispy Kreme has
responded by creating a whole wheat doughnut option that removes trans
fats from their products. Krispy Kreme has also eliminated the use of
artificial colors in their doughnuts. Also, they protect earth
environment with CO2 free production methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, although the concept of obtaining a healthier lifestyle has
become a rising trend, Krispy Kreme should remain afloat. Going out to
eat is a social habit exercised by most individuals which most likely
will not change.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Therefore, companies like Krispy Kreme can thrive,
but they will need to adjust their food options to stay competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme also gives back by participating in various social
contribution activities. Many of their stores sponsor children suffering
from hunger through the “Coin Collection for Love” event. Our commitment
to corporate social responsibility is also evident\
in our sponsorship for various charity events including disabled support
events, underprivileged children, neighbor support, etc.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:16&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technological Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to stay ahead of the competition, brands must embrace new
technology, however, in the food industry, technology has little
influence over the purchase and preparation of food. Newer technology
can be used to enhance efficiency, production, and distribution.
Although ecommerce is on the rise, this technology does not greatly
impact the food industry. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:17&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme has created an app in order to keep up with the millennial
demographic. Krispy Kreme’s Hot Light is a useful app that alerts its
followers when doughnuts are “hot off the line.” Users also have the
option of setting their preferred locations as well as offered
directions to others. Also to entice customers, Krispy Kreme has created
“My Krispy Kreme Treats” customer loyalty app. This app which can be
downloaded on both iOS and Android smartphones allows customers to earn
rewards point which are redeemable for free products at any of their
locations.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:18&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:18&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other technological advancements that Krispy Kreme has begun to
incorporate are paperless ordering, predictive modeling software, and
hand held computers for their delivery drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demographic Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme competes in both the restaurant industry and retail. In the
restaurant industry; which includes fast food, fast-casual, and full
service segments, Krispy Kreme provides a universal product and global
brand marketed to everyone, everywhere of all ages and incomes. Consumer
demographics are in line with the general population. The food service
industry is often affected by the preferences and perception of
consumer. Changes in preferences are a risk for Krispy Kreme, lessening
the demand for doughnuts, which reduce sales. Krispy Kreme also sells
doughnuts to supermarkets, gas stations, and retailers such as Wal-Mart
for resale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Industry Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;OLE_LINK1&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;OLE_LINK2&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Krispy Kreme competes within two major
industries and they are identified as the “Quick Service Restaurant” and
the “Baked Good Production” segments. QSR represents the largest segment
within the restaurant industry and is known for steady growth over long
periods of time. The Baked Good Production industry is recognized by
Krispy Kreme at the wholesale level and doesn’t require as many
resources as QSR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these markets are presently experiencing slow growth and overall
change because many channels are saturated and also because product
differentiation is hard to implement within the donut industry. Although
change and innovation do not occur, it still remains to be a very
appealing billion-dollar industry. Amongst Krispy Kreme, there are many
entities that also compete within the donut industry including, Dunkin
Donuts, Tim Horton’s, Shipley’s Do-Nuts, and other small sized bakeries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations within this environment share many structural
similarities. These similarities ultimately contribute toward the
overall attractiveness of the donut industry. In this particular
environment the common themes regarding structure were high fixed costs,
low switching costs for customers, relatively low product
differentiation, as well as the maximization of profits through royalty
payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to low product differentiation and the high concentration of
competitive rivals, these industries are openly known to be extremely
competitive. For example, Dunkin Donuts operates 14 times the amount of
retail locations Krispy Kreme has, although they still fall behind them
financially. Dunkin Donuts is Krispy Kreme’s closest competitor in
sales, product offering, and worldwide presence. This is the result of
Krispy Kreme outpacing Dunkin Donut in the area of important industry
metrics. Profit margins, return on assets, return on equity, and equity
to debt stand as the metrics dictating this particular industries
attractiveness. Additionally, this industry has very low customer
switching costs, which negatively affect customer loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The threat of new donut powerhouse entrants at the national level is
very low. First off, it takes a significant amount of capital to
establish a network of stores. According to the Business Journal, it
takes roughly a half of a million dollars to become a Krispy Kreme
franchisee.
(http://www.bizjournals.com/triad/blog/2013/01/how-much-would-it-cost-to-open-a.html)
Competing alongside the QSR’s largest firms makes it virtually
impossible to capture economies of scale. In order to compete on a
national scale, the right amount of brand equity must be established.
Brand equity is build through many investments made in time, as well as
advertisement dollars. Even though there isn’t much Krispy Kreme has to
worry about when it comes to potentially large corporations becoming a
new competitor, there is some vulnerability at the local level.
Mom-and-pop shops automatically pose as a legitimate threat toward
Krispy Kreme because the capital requirements for an individual firm are
not high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppliers have very little, if any, bargaining power mainly because most
businesses in this industry had a vertically intergraded business model.
Firms who choose to exercise this tactic gained access to a wide
availability of necessary raw materials.
(http://www.economist.com/node/13396061) It is also highly unlikely that
suppliers in the donut industry will enter the same business as its
clients. Companies such as Krispy Kreme have been known for locking in
contracts with their suppliers, further lessening the bargaining power
held by the suppliers. The low switching cost between vendors also is a
factor that plays against the suppliers as well. In fact, the only
buyers with the power to shake things up are firms in the wholesale
sales channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to its branding, customer-experience, secret recipes, and curiosity,
Krispy Kreme has positioned itself as the best differentiated brand in
the donut industry. Their belief of fluffily donuts over cake-textured
donuts is what largely separates Krispy Kreme and makes them stand out
in a well-received manner. By differentiating it’s main product as a
“premium donut” earned them a competitive edge and solidified Krispy
Kreme’s name within the industry.
(http://smallbusiness.chron.com/examples-differentiation-fast-food-69833.html)
Competitors of this industry attempt to expand revenues through coffee
sales, although the donut holds as absolute within the natural
performing environment. Due to the excellent efforts of differentiation,
the threat of substitution is low for Krispy Kreme unless donuts
completely disappear no matter how conscious consumers become. The
transition into conscious consumerism could unseeingly help sustain the
overall donut industry through healing overindulgence. As consumers
become increasingly aware, the chances of finding other useful or
therapeutic purpose for consuming donuts increase. For example, a
conscientious Krispy Kreme consumer of the future may determine that
they may want a fresh glazed donut not because they’re hungry, but
because they want to heighten their mood after a series of unfortunate
events. There are cases like this that occur highly often. Although the
desires of overindulgence are still present, this is due to the fact
that everyone in society has yet to evolve into a conscientious
consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intensity of rivalry among competitors Krispy Kreme faces is
moderate to high. Krispy Kreme has for a while, been outperforming all
of its competitors by a long shot. Both industries Krispy Kreme operates
in have highly concentrated amounts of competitive rivals, although many
of these channels are overly saturated. However, Krispy Kreme’s closest
competitor, Dunkin Donuts is in debt so deep that it is forced to
compete until the company goes black or an acceptable loss is set forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the analysis of The QSR and Baked Goods Production in which
Krispy Kreme competes, has exemplified that these are two highly
attractive and profitable industries. Through the extensive qualitative
and quantitative research of the environment in which Krispy Kreme
performs, high entry barriers, weak bargaining power from both seller
and buyer, along with weak product substitutions and moderate rivalry
among competitors were all identifiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 1995, Krispy Kreme moved into a new corporate headquarters,
reshuffled its management team, and prepared to expand nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To leverage the planned growth, the company relied on franchising
instead of opening company owned stores&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This allowed Krispy Kreme to receive a steady income flow from
royalty fees, expand its customer base for mix and equipment via
franchises, and inflate its brand recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By the end of 1999, the company’s portfolio included 144 shops in 27
states, and revenues had climbed to $220 million—up 40% from just
two years earlier&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme made its IPO in April 2000 with a split-adjusted price
of $9&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By the close of 2003, the stock was selling at a price just a bit
over $49 per share&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The company had expanded by 433 stores, had reached $700 million in
revenues, and had earned $88 million in operating profit&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As it turned out, the rapid expansion of the previous five years had
not been carefully or effectively planned&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As new franchises saturated the market and the novelty value of the
firm’s products faded, it became obvious that the early success of
many stores was sustainable&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many of the once-profitable stores began to flounder and, in May
2004, Krispy Kreme experienced its first unprofitable quarter as a
public company&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme implemented a new turnaround strategy that called for
cutting costs to a sustainable level as a path to prevent the firm’s
bankruptcy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Closed over 240 stores as the company retrenched to its stronghold
in the Southeast&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 2012, 66% of retail stores were located outside the United
States, with estimates of having 900 stores internationally by the
end of 2017&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stock price bottomed out at less than $4 a share in January 2008&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Revenue eventually increased at the end of 2012, Krispy Kreme looked
to open as many as 100 new stores domestic and internationally&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme earns the majority of revenue through the sale of
doughnuts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Doughnut sales comprise over 88% of all retail sales while the
remainder comes from selling beverage and complementary items&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintenance of consistent gross profit margins and modest revenue
growth of 4.5 and 11.4% in 2009 and 2010, respectively, have allowed
Krispy Kreme to contribute to its bottom line and return to
profitability&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Showed Net Income of $166 million and a 41% profit margin in fiscal
year ending January 2012&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme maintains wholesale contracts with a wide variety of
grocery stores, convenience stores, and other large
accounts—including Wal-Mart, Kroger, and Sheetz&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Value Chain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doughnut recipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unique taste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Produced, controlled, and consistent&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Distributed to all stores and franchises&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manufacturing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Design and manufacture of the doughnut making equipment&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is then sold to stores for profit and ensures consistency of
end product&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retail Distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mixture and equipment is distributed to large factory stores&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mix of factory stores that supply smaller stores&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Outsourced retail channels in service stations and Wal-Mart&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Worldwide Locations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Freshly baked and produced doughnuts each day&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Original glazed recipe&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simple product line&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”8.20625in” height=”9.270833333333334in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”8.52361111111111in”
height=”5.5in”}&lt;img src=&quot;media/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”8.208333333333334in”
height=”4.5in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”8.456944444444444in”
height=”9.622222222222222in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”7.947916666666667in”
height=”4.25in”}&lt;img src=&quot;media/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”8.447916666666666in”
height=”5.121527777777778in”}&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interactive Chart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”5.033333333333333in”
height=”6.729166666666667in”}&lt;img src=&quot;media/image8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.288888888888889in”
height=”3.9375in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”4.269444444444445in”
height=”4.864583333333333in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”4.25in” height=”3.8541666666666665in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Competitor Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Primarily competes in the Quick-Service Restaurant (QSR) segment of
the restaurant industry&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It also competes on a wholesale level in the Baked Goods Production
Industry&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competitive rivals include: Dunkin Donuts as their closest
competitor, Starbucks, Tim Horton’s, Shipley’s Do-Nuts and other
smaller bakeries&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dunkin Donuts has 628.2M in sales compared to Krispy Kreme having
just 403.22M&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dunkin Donuts is offered in 30 countries while Krispy Kreme is only
in 20 countries&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The firm is able to generate higher ROA and ROE as compared to
Dunkin Donuts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme has a significantly lower leverage ratio as compared to
Dunkin’s extremely high 195%&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They face less direct competition from McDonald’s, Starbucks, and
coffee shops because of their inability to market coffee sales&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme also faces some competition with pre-packaged goods
such as Little Debbie, Hostess and Sara Lee&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As is the case with its competitors, Krispy Kreme has made a
concerted effort as of late to expand revenues through coffee sales,
but the dominant element of the Krispy Kreme business model
continues to be doughnut sales&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dunkin Donuts generates approximately 60% of sales revenue from
coffee and other beverages; Krispy Kreme continues to lag far behind
in that regard with only 4% of its sales coming from coffee. They do
have a plan to double coffee sales within the next two years, but
they still don’t match up to companies such as Dunkin Donuts and
Starbucks&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of the largest concerns in the overall competitive environment
is the changing demands of consumers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As consumers become increasingly health conscious, the doughnut
industry becomes more vulnerable to the threat of substitution,
especially considering that each original glazed Krispy Kreme
doughnut has 200 calories and 12 grams of fat&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”5.5625in” height=”3.8645833333333335in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SWOT Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme Doughnuts, Inc. (KKD) is a very successful well known
company that possesses various strengths. Krispy Kreme’s appeal extends
to all demographics, which is an impressive strength to the company. KKD
are enjoyed by all individuals regardless of age, size, race, and
income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Krispy Kreme’s strengths is that they are a global firm. KKD has
established itself as a consumer brand with a consistent customer base
in both the United States and abroad. The company has branched out into
grocery and convenience stores in order to provide customers with more
accessibility to the brands products. Establishing their presence in
retail and wholesale environments proved to be a key component for this
company’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme generates revenue through four different business segments:
Company Stores, Domestic Franchises, International Franchises, and the
KK Supply Chain. Both the company’s stores and domestic franchises
operate similarly by earning revenue throughout retail operations as
well as wholesaling to grocery stores, convenience stores, and other
food venues. KKD has become quite popular in both convenience and
grocery stores. Due to the convenience, consumers can enjoy the famous
Krispy Kreme doughnuts without traveling to their retail locations and
instead purchase a quantity of donuts at a local supermarket. By selling
their products in stores Krispy Kreme has gained a huge advantage over
the competition. Majority of Krispy Kreme’s competitors, such as Dunkin
Donuts, do not sell their doughnut products in stores. This makes Krispy
Kreme a vertically integrated company with three retail unit
operations.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:19&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, Krispy Kreme earns most of their revenue from doughnut
sales, comprising over 88% of all retail sales. The company also
provides a wide variety of flavors for their doughnuts, coffee, and
bakery items. Since Krispy Kreme is such a well known brand they are
able to sell various types of memorabilia including mugs, hats, shirts,
and toys.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme’s concept of a “Doughnut Theater” has proven to be yet
strength for this company. The “Doughnut Theater” is a multi-sensory
experience that engulfs customers as they watch the doughnuts come off
the assembly line. The “Doughnut Theater” was introduced in the late
80’s when the company was experimenting with various innovative
marketing ideas. This concept exposes the doughnut-making equipment to
the customers inviting them to watch the doughnut making process in
stores. Visitors can observe the doughnuts through each phase starting
with the doughnuts being fried, to passing through a glazed waterfall,
and finally being then taken off the conveyer belt to be given to the
customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another innovative marketing technique that Krispy Kreme has implemented
is the “Hot Doughnuts Now” sign in most retail stores. Through this
technique, passing individuals are alerted when fresh doughnuts are hot
off the line. Not all locations participate in this method, but the ones
that do participate have received a lot of foot traffic and
word-of-mouth advertising. An additional strength of KKD is their desire
for growth and success. The company has worked very hard to be where
they are today and is willing to keep up the momentum in order to
continue their success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the most important strength of Krispy Kreme is their product.
Krispy Kreme Doughnuts are a unique product that simply cannot be
duplicated. Their competition will never be able to replicate a Krispy
Kreme Doughnut unless they discover the ingredients to the secret
recipe. KKD products set them apart from other doughnut shops and are
the core of the company. When you think of Krispy Kreme you think of
fresh, hot, glazed doughnuts and they have done a great job capturing
that part of the market. Even though they offer other products, such as
coffee and crullers, Krispy Kreme will always be known primarily for
their doughnuts.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:21&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Krispy Kreme has various strengths they also have just as many
weaknesses. The main weakness that KKD faces is that the majority of
their products are unhealthy. We are living in a more health conscious
world where people are concerned about what they are eating and worry
about how bad certain products are. Krispy Kreme has been placed on “The
Unhealthiest Foods” list for many years. The Krispy Kreme menu clearly
lacks healthy options which can be a major turn off for some consumers.
Their products are known as sweat treats and therefore the company is
having a hard time incorporating the health-conscious customer. The
negative health effects from eating too many doughnuts include: heart
conditions, high blood sugar, high blood pressure, and a lack of
nutrients. Krispy Kreme famously is known for their glazed doughnuts,
however the threatening truth that the consumption of doughnuts could
one day cause health issues is a becoming a growing problem for the
company. A Krispy Kreme Original Glazed doughnut is made from at least
50 ingredients, mostly artificial food additives that increase your
risks of cancer, diabetes, heart disease, allergies, and digestive
disorders. Sugar has been named Public Enemy No. 1 by the health
conscious percentage of the population and a Krispy Kreme doughnut
contain plenty of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the population becoming increasingly dependent on technology,
consumers want what they want, when they want it. Many companies have
taken this mentality into consideration and have made ordering online
readily available to the customer. Krispy Kreme has little to no
presence online, which is surprising considering the technologically
advanced world. KKD doesn’t have any options to order online and later
pick up their order in stores. This poses as a threat to the company
because individuals want easy and convenient shopping which the internet
makes that possible. Due to the inconvenience, consumers might decide to
purchase their doughnut elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue is that Krispy Kreme relies too much on their brand
recognition when in reality they should be up updating their service in
order to stay current. Krispy Kreme does little advertising and what
advertising they currently do is not aggressive enough to catch buyer’s
attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KKD menu is also a weakness. Krispy Kreme’s menu is weak and could
use some redesign to attract a larger target audience. By adding more
unique products to their menu, Krispy Kreme could potentially attract
more customers. The notion is that KKD sells only doughnuts when in
actuality they also have other baked goods and coffee. The company has
also been hit hard during times when the economy was doing poorly.
Krispy Kreme has had a handful of years where they were losing money and
close to going bankrupt.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:22&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme also struggles with rapid expansion as well. They had such
booming success in the company’s early years, but now moving too fast
can cause major problems for the company. The rapid expansion was not
fully thought or planned out and therefore resulted in exponential
growth in certain store locations and huge losses and struggles in
others. Due to this rapid expansion, Krispy Kreme has experienced their
first unprofitable quarter and cannot afford to let that happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another weakness that Krispy Kreme faces is their corporate structure.
There have been numerous board members, presidents, and CEO’s throughout
the company’s history that is has proven to be a disadvantage. In the
consumer or investors eyes, it is not a good look when a company’s CEO
is constantly changing. By the constant fluctuation of leadership and
management, to outsiders it appears as if the company does not know what
they are doing.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:23&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:23&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme has many possible opportunities to become more successful
than they have been in the past. As discussed earlier, healthier food
options pose as a weakness for Krispy Kreme which is a threat that they
should be improving. It is apparent that the introduction of the whole
wheat doughnut and the bite size doughnut options were not enough for
the company to be considered a healthy dinning option. Krispy Kreme also
introduced a number of juices, Naked Smoothie drinks, and yogurt options
which were implemented in a few retail locations. However, these changes
have not made a large impact. If Krispy Kreme focused on creating
healthier options to introduce to consumers, they will be able to
attract more people from the health conscious population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another helpful suggestion would be that Krispy Kreme should focus more
on the coffee market. KKD currently offers a coffee option but it is not
as successful as predicted. The coffee market is one that is very easy
for KKD to enter because their product goes great with coffee. When
people think of breakfast they instantly think of coffee and doughnuts
because they go hand and hand. If Krispy Kreme adds new flavors or
options for their coffee and advertises them properly then it is
conceivable that more people would be attracted to their offer. Many
people don’t know that Krispy Kreme currently sells coffee, therefore
marketing correctly is the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another opportunity for growth and success for Krispy Kreme are foreign
markets. The company has always done well internationally but further
expansion could lead to an increase in revenue and brand recognition.
KKD first international shop was opened in 2001 in Canada, just outside
of Toronto. Now Krispy Kreme has stores and operates in 24 different
countries around the world. Each store offers different products
depending on the country in which they are operating. For example, in
Australia Krispy Kreme offers the Mudcake doughnut which is a devil food
cake doughnut glazed and topped with a chocolate coating. In South Korea
they offer the Tiramisu Soft Ring doughnut which is a thick smooth ring
doughnut with mascarpone cheese filling, cocoa powder, and espresso for
a blend of taste. Krispy Kreme has proven to be successful in foreign
markets but continuing their growth domestically is something that they
should strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the closest Krispy Kreme location in relation to Boston is
located in Connecticut, which is approximately 80.28 miles away. Because
their brand recognition is so strong, they will be able to slowly begin
opening more stores across the United States while also keeping in mind
the problems they faced with rapid expansion in the past. By advancing
advertising efforts Krispy Kreme can remain relevant and keep their
consumers in the loop. Krispy Kreme does not actively participate in
much advertisement which is a main concern that needs improvement. If
they become more prevalent in TV commercials, ads on the radio, and
social media marketing then they might have a chance to hit a new
audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krispy Kreme Doughnuts faces many threats due to the market that they
are present in. The biggest threat that Krispy Kreme faces is their
competition. They have many competitors both domestic and abroad in
various sizes. Over the past two decades, competition in the fast-food
market has increased. Krispy Kreme’s biggest competitors include:
Dunkin’ Donuts, Tim Hortons, Starbucks, and local bakeries. Dunkin’
Donuts has a unique selling proposition stating, “America Runs on
Dunkin.” Historically, Dunkin’ Donuts is the world’s largest coffee and
donut shop, serving more than 3 million coffees a day. This competitor
alone makes it very difficult for Krispy Kreme to attempt further
tackling the world of coffee. Dunkin’ Donuts and Starbucks have almost
all of the coffee market locked up leaving Krispy Kreme with the
challenge of trying to break through.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:24&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:24&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Horton’s, which is a Canadian based company, focuses on “always
fresh” coffee, baked goods and home-style breakfast, and lunches in a
quick-service restaurant. Another threat they face is competition in
local bakeries. Many people like the idea of going to their local “mom
and pop” bakery to buy pastries rather than supporting a chain such as
Krispy Kreme. Rivals are concerned about Krispy Kreme’s rapid growth,
market share gains, and erosion of their own market positions.
Therefore, competitors may be compelled to rejuvenate their menus,
product quality, and strategies in order to stay ahead of the possible
advances of Krispy Kreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health conscious consumers are also a threat to Krispy Kreme. If
consumers continue to be health and nutrition conscious, leading them to
avoid doughnuts, the company may face a continued slow market growth and
flat and diminishing sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strategies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning with Krispy Kreme’s core competencies, leadership,
individuality, and philanthropy are the main themes that the
organization has built their business upon. The resources that Krispy
Kreme has accumulated throughout its existence are in a large thanks to
the solid foundation ratified, which in return fostered a sustainable
environment safe to compete in. The great internal leadership from
Morgan has enabled Krispy Kreme the opportunity to exercise its
resources in compliance with its core competencies, strengths, and
capabilities. Therefore, in order to further increase the overall
efficiency and effectiveness of a business, its operational strategies
must be updated or innovated once self-identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources such as refined management tools, training manuals, and
hands-on employee training are often under utilized even though these
tools can do great damage especially if practiced behind great
leadership. Since Krispy Kreme leadership has suggested that it is now
aiming at greater investments in human capital, I think it it’s time for
the firm to enhance its ambiance by incorporating the human touch. Brand
equity is a very noticeable strength that Krispy Kreme can still expand
upon with the help of employees whose purpose is to create a resonating
experience outside of the donut theater. For example, changing the
climate of a Krispy Kreme retail store to attract young professionals or
the whole millennial generation will be the best target market to
monetize domestically. Millennials makeup the majority of the people in
the United States and are also the most educated generation to exist.
Since the dining spaces have a quick turnover anyways, innovating that
space into a “think tank” “incubator” or simply a place that attracts
the most valuable element of any economy – an idea. This is a low cost
implementation that wouldn’t require significant change to the
infrastructure of the firm. The core competencies of Krispy Kreme
reflect an accurate depiction of the millennial essence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another route leadership could consider going in the implication of
joint ventures where a bakery and medical marijuana dispensary would
both operate. The joint ventures would begin in states that have already
completely legalized both the use of recreational and medical marijuana.
Starting in states that have no laws regarding the usage of personal
marijuana would prevent adverse reactions or cultural shock to areas
that aren’t ready. Individuality, leadership, and philanthropy also tie
in fairly accurately regarding the essence of marijuana. Furthermore,
the real excitement of this implementation comes from the added revenue
stream. Just like donuts, marijuana is now being package and sold as a
commodity. This cash crop currently has one of the highest demands,
while generating millions of dollars that eventually can be reinvested
back into a local community. If this measure were to be executed, Krispy
Kreme would further differentiate itself, separating itself from the
current industries it identifies with. Eventually this has the potential
to become the first American version of the European coffee house model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final implementation strategy suggested would be the most simplistic
of the three regarding execution. The single most important thing all
brands must make sure they are active on social media outlets. This is
an essential for all brands because it’s important to have an open
channel of dynamic communication toward your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cluteinstitute.com/ojs/index.php/JBCS/article/view/4771/4861&quot;&gt;http://www.cluteinstitute.com/ojs/index.php/JBCS/article/view/4771/4861&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/Our-Story&quot;&gt;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/Our-Story&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.krispykreme.com/about&quot;&gt;https://www.krispykreme.com/about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/&quot;&gt;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cluteinstitute.com/ojs/index.php/JBCS/article/view/4771/4861&quot;&gt;http://www.cluteinstitute.com/ojs/index.php/JBCS/article/view/4771/4861&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/Our-Story&quot;&gt;https://www.krispykreme.com/about/Our-Story&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://study.com/academy/lesson/code-of-business-conduct-ethics-standards-examples.html&quot;&gt;http://study.com/academy/lesson/code-of-business-conduct-ethics-standards-examples.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://investor.shareholder.com/synaptics/corporate-governance-document.cfm?documentid=4754&quot;&gt;http://investor.shareholder.com/synaptics/corporate-governance-document.cfm?documentid=4754&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://investor.shareholder.com/synaptics/corporate-governance-document.cfm?documentid=4754&quot;&gt;http://investor.shareholder.com/synaptics/corporate-governance-document.cfm?documentid=4754&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&quot;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harbott.com/2011/01/12/analysing-strategic-forces-that-shape-industries-with-pest/&quot;&gt;http://www.harbott.com/2011/01/12/analysing-strategic-forces-that-shape-industries-with-pest/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&quot;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:13&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&quot;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:13&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:14&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.angelfire.com/indie/dannydiab/fin821kkd.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.angelfire.com/indie/dannydiab/fin821kkd.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:14&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:15&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&quot;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:16&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krispykreme.com/about/Philanthropy&quot;&gt;http://www.krispykreme.com/about/Philanthropy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:16&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:17&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&quot;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/51583175/Casestudy-on-Krispy-Kreme-doughnut#scribd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:17&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:18&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hotnews.krispykreme.com/blog/rotating-featured-content/krispy-kreme-rolls-out-new-customer-loyalty-app-select-markets&quot;&gt;http://hotnews.krispykreme.com/blog/rotating-featured-content/krispy-kreme-rolls-out-new-customer-loyalty-app-select-markets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:18&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:19&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://mergent.firstresearch-learn.com/industry.aspx?chapter=0&amp;amp;pid=414 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:19&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/business/companies/krispy-kreme-doughnuts-inc/index.html&quot;&gt;http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/business/companies/krispy-kreme-doughnuts-inc/index.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:21&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://mergent.firstresearch-learn.com/industry.aspx?chapter=0&amp;amp;pid=414 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:21&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:22&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://subscriber.hoovers.com/H/company360/overview.html?companyId=53559000000000 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:22&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:23&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://subscriber.hoovers.com/H/company360/overview.html?companyId=53559000000000 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:23&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:24&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/panosmourdoukoutas/2013/04/25/dunkin-brands-or-krispy-kreme/&quot;&gt;http://www.forbes.com/sites/panosmourdoukoutas/2013/04/25/dunkin-brands-or-krispy-kreme/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:24&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
<category term="Krispy Kreme" />
<category term="Case Study" />
<summary>Krispy Kreme Case</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Google - Case Study</title>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Google/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google - Case Study" />
<published>2016-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
<updated>2016-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Google</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Google/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;h.gjdgxs&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Robyn Crean, Jason DiCarlo,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Granville, Isaiah King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Company Background 3 - 8&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;General Environmental Analysis 9 - 16&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Industry Analysis 17 - 24&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competitor Analysis 25 - 28&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Internal Analysis 29 - 32&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SWOT 33 - 38&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strategies 39 - 42&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Works Cited 43 - 45&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Company Background&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America’s top search engine company, Google Inc., was founded in 1996 by
Sergey Brin and Larry Page. The two met at Stanford University where the
concept of Google began simply as a research project. This project
transformed into a search engine that was originally designed to examine
connecting links between web pages in order to determine a site’s
authority. In 1998, Page and Brin set up their first data center in
Page’s dorm. As their project slowly began to grow, the duo was noticed
by fellow Stanford Alumni, David Filo, the creator of Yahoo, who
encouraged them to continue their efforts.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their next step was to seek out investors to back them up. Andy
Bechtolsheim, one founder of Sun Microsystems, invested $100,000 in the
company after receiving a demo of their search technology. Eventually,
Page and Brin were able to raise over $1million. Now with plenty of
investors to support the duo this was the perfect time for the company,
which was in the midst of a dot-com boom, to emerge into the market.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Inc. was officially established on September 7, 1998 in a
friend’s garage in California. The name “Google” was derived from a
misspelling of Page’s original name, “Googol,” which is a mathematical
term for the number 1 followed by 100 zeroes.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  By the end of 1999,
Brin and Page dropped out of Stanford’s Graduate Program in order to
concentrate on the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By mid-1999, Google received a $25million round of venture capital
funding and processing 500,000 queries per day. In their humble
beginnings, Google served over 10,000 queries daily and quickly gained a
reputation as a trustworthy source of information.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; By 2000,
Google.com released different versions of the site offering various
languages such as: French, German, Italian, Swedish, Finnish, Spanish,
Portuguese, Dutch, Norwegian, Danish, Chinese, Japanese, and Korean. Now
that the website could be used internationally, Google’s growth
continued.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2002, the Google News Service was launched. This service offers users
a “comprehensive up-to-date news coverage, aggregated from sources all
over the world.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Later in 2005 Google released: Google Maps, Google
Earth, and iGoogle. These services gave Google a larger range of
products in order to reach out to an even larger audience.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new verb, “to Google” was officially added to the Oxford English
Dictionary on June 15, 2005. In 2006, Google took a huge step forward by
purchasing YouTube. YouTube, the world’s most popular online video site,
hosts users who are watching approximately 4billion hour’s worth of
videos each month as well as uploading 72 hours worth of videos every
minute. Originally, YouTube planned on operating independently, while
its co-founders and 67 employees worked within Google.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2007, Gmail became available to the general public. Venturing into
the email market was a huge step for Google. Also in 2007, Google made
its largest acquisition to date, purchasing the online advertising firm,
DoubleClick, for $3.1billion. Over the next couple of years Google
continued to introduce products that would keep them relevant as well as
showing diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Google Chrome, the company’s first web browser,
began in 2008 and quickly took off. Following Google Chrome was the
release of their first Android-based phone, the T-Mobile G1. The
following year, Sergey Brin and Larry Page were named the fifth most
powerful people in the world by Forbes magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, the long awaited Google +1 was launched. Google launched a
promotional video for the +1 button explaining the social feature. “When
you click +1, you’re telling your friends, your family and the rest of
the world, ‘This is something you should check out!”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This feature,
which is very similar to Facebook’s “Like” button, was Google’s attempt
to branch out into the social media market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Google offers many services and devices but they are best known
for their search engine. Google has branched out into various services
over the years which has helped them become the successful company they
are today. Their primary and most successful service is Google Search.
Google revealed that they are procession 100billion searches per month
or 1.2trillion per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gmail is by far the best email platform in the world. Embraced by
millions it has changed the way many individuals communicate. Google has
opened up the email market by diminishing the worry of storage by
allowing users unlimited space, allowing them to save as many emails as
they deem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Maps has been around for quite some time but didn’t really become
successful until the app was installed onto phones.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Originally,
Google Maps used to be a case of printed off addresses with scrawled
directions. Today, with its updated technology, Google Maps is a popular
application used by drivers in order to navigate.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google News was launched in 2009 and remains one of the top sources for
news on a daily basis. On Google’s website, Google Earth is described as
a “virtual globe, map and geographical information program.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Apps are used by people worldwide on a daily basis. These
features include Google Calendar, Google Talk (Chat), and Google
Docs/Slides/Sheets. The newly popular Google Docs, Slides, and Sheets
are productivity apps that allow individuals to create different types
of documents online, working on them in real time with other people, as
well as storing them in a Google Drive online free of cost. Another
innovative feature is that Google Docs automatically saves ones work to
their drive, elimination the fear of losing all material if ones
computer crashes or shuts down.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:13&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Alerts is a small but useful little product that many people
depend on to keep them informed of personal or brand mentions. Other
features that Google offers thar are usually overlooked include: Picasa,
FeedBurner, Google Translate, Google Books Blogger, Google Street View,
and Orkut. There are other tools used by students and big companies as
well including: Google Scholar, Google Analytics, Google Ventures,
Adwords, Google Voice, and Google Finance. The Scholar, Analytic, and
Finance tools are the most popular in the business world and are
extremely reliable providing real time information.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:14&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has also bought other companies in order to add more to their
resume. Google’s first acquisition was the Usenet Company, Deja
News,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and its services then became Google Groups.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:16&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Next, Google
acquired Dodgeball,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:17&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:17&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a social networking service company,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:18&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:18&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and
eventually replaced it with Google Latitude.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:19&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:19&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other acquisitions include web application company JotSpot,&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which
became Google Sites. Later, voice over IP’s company, GrandCentral, later
became Google Voice, and video hosting service company Next New Networks
became YouTube Next Lab and Audience Development Group.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:21&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Google has also ventured out into the mobile cell phone market.
They sell a range of Nexus and Android phones, which are not yet Apple’s
level, but are quickly gaining attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google offers products that most individuals need or could use on a
daily basis, with the list continuing to grow. By increasing their
product diversity to their list, Google is successfully adapting with
the times and staying relevant. Today, Google may be a huge success
however staying on top is an important key factor in their future
success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;General Environmental Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technological Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is a popular search engine that uses text-matching techniques to
find web pages that are important and relevant to a user’s search
handling more than three billion searches per day.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:22&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Google’s primary
technological advance is its web search functionality. It is an
indispensable feature of the Internet as well as an essential factor to
its business.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:23&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:23&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Due to the never ending change in technology,
programmers and engineers are working constantly to ensure search
results are as relevant as possible. More time is devoted to this
process than any other Google product. Google is not only a search
engine but also provides many services, tools, and products through its
website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Apps is a set of web applications provided by Google. These
applications include Gmail, Google Docs, Google Calendar, Google Mobile,
and Google Sites.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:24&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:24&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Gmail is a free e-mail service created by Google
that provides users with storage for their personal or business messages
and offers the ability to search for specific messages. This program
automatically organizes messages into a conversation thread and has an
advanced spam-filtering technique.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:25&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:25&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anther app produced by Google is Google Docs. Google Docs is an online
word processor, presentation, spreadsheet, and form application. This
app allows numerous users to collaborate together in “real-time” to
create, share, open, and edit documents online simultaneously. Forms can
be created directly on the web interface, or users an upload existing
documents for group online editing. All documents edited or created
online can be saved to a user’s computer in various formats. As a useful
feature for users, Google servers automatically save all file data In
order to avoid data loss.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:26&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:26&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Although Google Docs is less
“feature-rich” as full desktop applications, such as Microsoft Office,
Google Docs is available for use to anyone with a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Calendar is a calendar web application provided by Google
allowing users to view, create, and manage their calendar events. It
allows for online and mobile access, synchronization to applications and
mobile devices, event reminders, and easy sharing with friends or
coworkers.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:27&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:27&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This software allows users to drag-and-drop in order to
easily move events around from various dates or hours without having to
reload another page. It also supports various viewing modes including:
daily, weekly, monthly, and agenda views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile computing is becoming the future of technology and the Internet,
therefore Google created Google Mobile in order to stay ahead of the
mobile trend. Google Mobile is free applications of services provided by
Google in order to enhance a user’s mobile experience. These apps can be
used on any mobile device and include Gmail, Search, Maps, and
YouTube.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:28&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:28&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;h.30j0zll&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Another popular
technological trend is cloud computing. Therefore, Google created Google
Cloud, a cloud computing platform. This cloud is a network made of
approximately one million servers which store data. Each server dies
after three years and is replaced by a newer and faster server allowing
Google’s cloud to regenerate its computing power. Google Cloud Storage
allows for world-wide storage and retrieval of any amount of data at any
time. Google Cloud Storage allows users to store date on Google’s
infrastructure with high reliability, performance, and
availability.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:29&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:29&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google recently launched its new Google Apps Marketplace, the first
viable platform for cloud computing from third parties. This product is
an online store that ultimately aims to assist individuals and
organizations to discover, purchase, and deploy integrated cloud web
applications that work with Google Apps or third party software.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:30&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:30&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way Google is fighting to stay the best in the field of
technology by purchasing various start-up companies that allow Google to
benefit from the dynamism and creativity that these companies may bring.
These companies specialties range in variety of fields such as:
security, advertising, video, file sharing, shopping, and mobile
technology.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:31&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:31&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another form of technology besides apps is server hardware. Google,
unlike other companies, does not purchase its servers but instead builds
their own. In 2006, Google was ranked the fourth largest server
manufacturer in the world. Google continues to differ from other
companies when it comes to their storage. Instead of investing in costly
devices, Google uses a low-price, high-redundancy model. Lastly, another
item that Google obtains at cheaper prices is bandwidth. Google pays
minimal prices for bandwidth due to their large-scale purchase of “dark
fiber.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:32&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is not only a company providing internet services and mobile
applications but also have a line of hardware products. The Google Store
invites consumers to Google’s hardware products that include phones,
tablets, Chromebooks, TV &amp;amp; audio devices, and various accessories for
said products. As technological advances increase, Google will continue
to be successful with their original search engine and apps while also
venturing out into various types of hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demographic Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is targeted generally towards everyone however, has a relatively
young user base. About 60% of Americans visit Google weekly, most users
being young, under 50, and college educated. Google is less affected by
the ages of Baby Boomers compared to other companies which depend on the
50-60 year-old demographic group. The ratio of males to females is not
affected because internet searching is not a gender specific issue. The
company will further benefit from traditional or paternalistic societies
begin using the internet more frequently.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:33&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Economic Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the United States is in a period of recession, companies like
Google are not affected because search and internet-based advertisements
have become a staple in society and the economy. Google’s focus is
currently on highly targeted measurable advertising which makes the
company recession-proof.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:34&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Google has gained an increase in demand
for its services and increasing profit levels due to more business
advertising. The company is expected to increase in profit levels
regardless of the state of the economy due to the growing trend of
businesses advertising online.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:35&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries such as South Africa, India, China, and the United Kingdom
have had increases in their Gross Domestic Products (GDP) which could
potentially be a positive factor for Google. If these countries continue
to grow at stable rates, Google’s internal and external investments will
be high in numbers. The growing amount of users on the internet and
search engine will positively affect Google.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:36&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:36&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates can both positively and negatively affect an
organization. Google relies primarily on investments, which come with
interest rates. As these rates gradually increase over time in a country
Google will benefit. For example, in the UK the rate average is around
8.2%, and in the U.S. rates stand at 6.1%. The more companies that have
an increase in rates and money, the more likely they will be willing to
spend on advertisements, a service provided by Google.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:37&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:37&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inflation rates are a problem for customers whereas companies benefit
from it. The U.S., U.K., India, and China have recorded averages in
inflation rates of 2.5% - 9.5% annually. From this, raw materials become
more expensive resulting in companies to increase prices of their
products. As the product price increases, so does the cost of a Google
advertisement, resulting in more profits for the company.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:38&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:38&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Political Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most governments do not have legal or political laws for online
information sharing, therefore Google’s operations remain unaffected.
However, over time Google has received numerous concerns from customers
in regards to user privacy. The company then responded by adding a
privacy link to their home page. This link brings users to Google’s
Privacy Center page where individuals can learn more about Google’s
policies in regards to political and legal issues.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:39&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:39&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;39&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another legal issue Google faces is copyright. This company stores
copies of third party web pages and images on their servers, some of
which are copyright infringements. In response, Google released a
Copyright Information Page providing information on digital information
as well as links to notify Google and the U.S. Copyright Office of any
suspected infringement.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:40&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:40&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Government is posing as a threat towards Google in regards
to censoring search results. China has created a barrier against Google
by creating regulations that forbid the search engine from operation on
their terms. In 2013, the Chinese Government created a surveillance
system called the Golden Shield, which monitors civilian use of the
internet.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:41&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:41&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sociolocultural Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sociocultural trends affect the way that customers respond to Google’s
products. Today, there is an increase in use of social media. Although
social media sites offer online advertising for companies, such as
Google, social media poses as a threat. As the use of these sites
increase, so do competing sites such as Facebook.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:42&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:42&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet and search applies to most cultures worldwide, therefore
Google does not face a geographic dependence. Google has 20 offices in
the U.S. and other locations in over 30 countries. Google now offers
personalized search engines for over 115 countries. As language support
improves the company will likely gain market shares. Once computers
become more affordable in various countries, those in economically
disadvantaged countries will be able to gain access to the internet for
the first time. Google will then be able to introduce these new users to
its search engine and productivity products.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:43&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:43&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Industry Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a qualitative and quantitative analysis of the Web Search
segment, the standout characteristics include: Intense Rivalries,
Diversification, and Vertically Integrated Business Modeling. The focus
of this industry analysis is Google, although it operates within several
different industry codes made up by the North American Industry
Classification System (NAICS) and Standard Industry Codes (SIC).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:44&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:44&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An understanding of the essence of the climate in which Google performs
an examination of its key competitors is necessary. The atmosphere, or
climate, of the U.S Web Search segment that Yahoo, Microsoft, and Google
perform within has been developed by the post-industrial society
beginning to unfold. The post-industrial society is the stage of
society’s development when the service sector generates more wealth than
the manufacturing sector of the economy. The important connection
between post-industrial societies and the firms competing in the Web
Search segment is the fact that these companies function as services,
opposed to manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this analysis, “post-industrial” is used in an economical or
sociological manner. The post-industrialized society is characterized by
the increased value of knowledge. In an economical sense,
post-industrialization is characterized by employment growing faster in
the third and fourth sector in contrast to employment in the primary and
secondary sector. This results in the third and fourth sector having the
most influence in the economy. Thus, the “impact of the expert” will
grow larger allowing power to be monopolized by knowledge. Since the
third and fourth sectors are essentially knowledge-oriented, a
restructuring of education is likely to occur. Post-industrial societies
are oriented around places of knowledge in which influence the
production of experts. Consequently, the demographic that will benefit
the most in the post-industrial society are young urban professionals
due to their effective yet efficient utilization of technology,
information, and networks.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:45&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:45&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;45&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industrialization is the large-scale introduction of manufacturing,
advanced technical enterprises, and other productive economic activity
into an area, society, or country. The definition of this era contains a
timestamp along with an expiration date because the concept of
large-scale manufacturing is no longer under developed. The factors that
were once the main driving force of the industrial economy, labor and
mass manufacturing, quickly are beginning to fade. The new factors
driving the post-industrial economics and society are networks,
information, data, and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New firms such as Uber, AirBnB, and Kickstarter are beginning establish
themselves as early adapters in this new age by designing business
models around the projected economical driving forces. There are also
many already existing firms who are embracing this economical and social
change. Google, Yahoo, Microsoft, and Apple are amongst the world’s top
innovators because they are disrupting the concept of an industry. These
firms have the capability of existing under a single company although
they may operate within dozens of industries. Thanks to the increased
value of knowledge from companies and consumers, concepts such as crowd
sourcing and vertically integrated business models are beginning to help
develop the post-industrialization era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web Search and Advertising segment is considered to be under the
broad category of Internet services, in which the post-industrial era
has birthed. The Search Engine segment has only three direct competitors
who own substantial market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to properly evaluate this segments attractiveness, Porter’s
Five Forces Model will be used to measure and examine the competitive
playing field. Microsoft Corporation’s Bing, Yahoo Inc.’s Yahoo Search,
and Google Inc.’s Google Search are key competitors amongst each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest threats may come from search engines within websites and
apps that offer more than just searches, such as Amazon and Facebook.
Thus, the possibility of an existing competitor who doesn’t have a
substantial amount of the search engine market share is moderate to
high.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:46&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:46&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The post-industrial economy has enabled Facebook and Amazon
compete naturally within the same environment as Google Search because
the ability and function of “searching” is critical online or offline,
therefore the implementation of a search function has been integrated on
many levels across technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the threat of substitution dangerously high for Google is the
amount of traffic that Facebook and Amazon experience. According to
Alexa.com, the most popular referred website regarding traffic analytics
shows that Facebook.com ranks second domestically and globally. Amazon
also ranks very high in annual traffic that could potentially lead to
the substitution of Google. Although Google ranks number one globally
and domestically, the threat of one of these key competitors developing
an improved search engine still exists.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:47&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:47&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social aspect of Facebook, or the consumerist outlet like Amazon,
both have a greater need for a more optimized search engine. For
example, if one needed to know what kind what the process, or materials
needed, in order to replace a radio within a 2015 Ford Mustang. The
function of an optimized search engine within Amazon.com would allow for
consumers learn what they could from Google while also providing the
most popular online marketplace. This would be good for Amazon because
it will increase user retention by forcing them to stay one website for
access to knowledge and a marketplace. This would also lead increased
traffic for Amazon because there would be less of a need for Google’s
weaker search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, if Amazon and Facebook were to develop a stronger search
engine, Google would be virtually useless. However, if Google continued
to dominate the science of search engineering, competitors who pose a
threat of substitution, will still have full functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What prevents Facebook, Amazon, or any new entrant from competing within
this segment is due to the complexity, popularity, and strength of
Google’s search engine. The differentiation of Google’s service brings
with it a strong customer loyalty by providing unique searching
experiences acts as one of the strongest barrios block new entrants from
this segment. Web search functionality is ultimately how Google began
and still remains at the heart of what they do today. Google’s web
search is considered to be indispensable due to its investments within
research and development and human capital. These investments have
allowed the programmers and engineers of Google to constantly make
search results and page rankings as relevant as possible. Google’s
searching service also has the global market firmly grasped. The firm’s
web search service is operates 160 localized country/regional domains.
Google also offers the ability to search for results in 130 different
languages. The low threat of new entries also comes from within Google’s
vertically integrated business model. What this allows is instead of
buying server hardware from HP, Dell, and IBM, Google instead creates
their own servers. The Gartner Group, and information technology
research and advisory firm estimated in 2006 that Google was the fourth
largest server manufacturer in the world. The expense of storage is
unusually low for a firm such as Google because they invest in hardware
that isn’t expected to be of high quality but instead low in
price.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:48&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:48&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; There are wide spread rumors of Google paying very little
costs for bandwidth usage. Costs for bandwidth are believed to be so low
due to the investments Google made in “dark fiber” – fiber optic cable
that was laid in the dot-com era. As of April 2010, Millward Brown
Optimor, a consultancy who issues annual reports aimed at measuring the
intangible worth of brands, named Google to be in the top four of that
category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Google isn’t worried about the threat of substitution. The
threat of substitution is low because Google essentially depends on the
Internet’s existence and functionality for its survival, rather than
traditionally performing within a competitive environment. While its
competitors where spending millions on building brand during the dot-com
boom, Google instead focused on quietly building upon its strongest
barrier of entrance, the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most effective ways to remove the threat of supplier power is
through the implementation of a vertically intergraded business model.
This worked in the favor of Google as an advantage because it removed
the dependence of outsourcing less effective components from other
firms. This allowed Google to customize their servers and also become
the fourth largest sever manufacturer in the world. Google also holds
immense supplier power toward its consumers through Adwords. Adwords has
become an easy and common way for companies and individuals to generate
revenue through their websites. Other competitors within the Web Search
segment face more of a threat from suppliers due to strategy of
outsourcing. This threat at large isn’t much worry for these competitors
because hardware such as servers has become commodities for large
business. Although, storage along with bandwidth have been known to be
harder or more expensive to obtain suppliers. The chance of any of these
suppliers entering the Search Engine segment is highly unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously, Google and its competitors generally depend on
the Internet’s existence and functionality for their survival. Since
Google and the other competitors of the Web Search segment provide a
service that is free, there’s virtually no buying power that’s even able
to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the utilization of Porters Five Forces model, the Web search
segment has proved itself to be attractive. Competitors within this
segment, such as Google, have set barriers for substitution or new
entrants very high. Google has invested incomparable amounts of research
and development into its Web search service versus its competitors Yahoo
and Bing. In 2009, Google spent 12% of its operating expense dollars
versus Microsoft who spent 15%. Even though Microsoft seemingly spent
more on research and development, it is important to note that Microsoft
is in the business of hardware, so it’s important that one assumes that
not all of that 15% is being allocated to its Web Search segment. In
2013, Google was the top 9^th^ spender globally in research and
development.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:49&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:49&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;49&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is in the business of advertising and EMarketer estimates that
Google’s 2015 search ad revenue will grow to $44 billion worldwide, a
54.5% share, with Microsoft and Yahoo combined taking just 6.5%.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:50&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:50&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
The threat of any new entrance seems likely to be the biggest threat
within this segment, although it is highly unlikely. Indirect
competitors such as Facebook and Amazon have almost all the resources to
enter this segment as a top competitor. The amount of intellectual
capital these two competing firms contain is still not enough to take
the top spot because Google has developed its service intensively for
more than two decades. The algorithms and web crawling techniques Google
has developed has prevented any substitute or new entry within the Web
Search segment from outperforming the firm, almost creating a
monopolized segment. The result of these segments and their
attractiveness also rely on the low position that buyers and suppliers
have. The vertically integrated business model Google has implemented
has prevented suppliers from having any type of power. Other competitors
face a low to medium threat due to not having full control of their
needed supplies, although hardware such as servers are being sold as
commodities to large business. Buyer power is relatively low, although
Google and Bing’s Web Search service income depends on the purchase of
advertising space that individuals and companies seek out. But since Web
Search is most commonly utilized as a free service, buying power doesn’t
have much influence. The completive environment of the Web Search
segment has arguably become a duopoly that is dictated by Google and
Bing. Bing and Yahoo’s search engine combined, make up 32% percent of
the U.S. market, while Google accounts for 64%. Although it seems
unlikely that Bing will overtake Google, the search engines within
Facebook, Amazon, and other sites could shift how Internet search
segments perform and compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Competitor Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:51&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:51&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;           **Google**   **Yahoo**   ------------ ------------ -----------   Market Cap   495.93B      33.20B   Employees    59,976       12,500   Revenue      71.76B       4.95B   Net Income   15.44B       242.18M   EPS          23.72        0.26
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competitive industries that Google operates in cannot be classified
by using only one or two industries. Its diversified portfolio spans a
wide array of products and services, all revolving around the
opportunities brought on by the advent of the Internet. For these
reasons Google’s main competitors include: Yahoo, Microsoft, and Apple.
These companies are diversified to include several industries with the
common goal of each company, to provide innovative products and services
that offer consumers with the ability to access, distribute, create, and
use computer data. For this analysis we will focus on the search engine
product offered by these companies, with Yahoo being the closest
competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1994, Stanford University students Jerry Wang and David Flo created
Yahoo when they developed “an Internet bookmark list and directory of
interesting sites.” Ultimately in 2000, Yahoo formed a partnership with
Google that allowed them to power Yahoo’s organic results thus
effectively introducing “their largest competitor to the world,” making
Google a “household name” and in the process, cutting its own throat.
Five years later Google was out performing Yahoo and by 2009 it had
captured 70% of the search engine market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.0in” height=”3.5in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As shown in the above table from November 2015, Google’s Market
Capitalization is approximately fifteen times that of Yahoo’s. In terms
of Market Share for search engines, Google has approximately 69% of the
market, Yahoo has 9%, Bing has 12% and Baidu (China) has 7% of the
market.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:52&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:52&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;52&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.0in” height=”3.5in”}&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:53&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:53&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has the highest revenue out of the three search engines,
however, when you break the numbers down and look purely at advertising
revenue from the search engine, Google Search edges out Bing by about
$8million.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:54&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:54&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Overall, Google derives approximately 99% of its
revenue from advertising. Although Yahoo is clearly not competing, they
have recently shifted their focus on their search engine and are finally
seeing their hard work pay off. Yahoo also stretched out the one
positive revenue streak it had going, increasing its search revenue
year-over-year for the fifth straight quarter.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:55&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:55&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;55&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Value Chain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.75625in” height=”2.736111111111111in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google gathers all the web users it can by inviting them to use its
top-rated search product with highly relevant results delivered
promptly. Then, through assorted advertisements it directs these same
web users in the form of traffic to its advertising partners who
transform the traffic into sales on their sites. Google adds value not
only by directing a quantity of web users to specific sites, but also by
sorting the pre-qualified visitors using keyword association and search
history to recognize users’ interests. Google ensures that the users who
are directed to a partner site are more likely to purchase a product
there.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:56&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:56&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.0in” height=”4.726388888888889in”}&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:57&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:57&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;57&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see Google’s Revenue has increased over the past three years.
An increase in revenue has lead to a constant increase in Net Income.
Since we are focusing on the Search Engine side of Google, with their
revenue coming from advertisements, they reported advertising revenues
of $59,065,000,000 in 2014 and $50,547,000,000 in 2013. Their revenues
from Google Network Members’ websites include revenues generated
primarily through advertising programs including: AdSense for search,
AdSense for content, AdExchange, AdMob, and DoubleClick Bid Manager. In
this multi-device world, Google generates their advertising revenues
increasingly from mobile phones and newer advertising formats, and the
margins from the advertising revenues from these sources have generally
been lower than those from desktop computers and tablets.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:58&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:58&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;58&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.0in” height=”5.895138888888889in”}&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:59&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:59&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/image11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;{width=”6.0in” height=”6.375in”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SWOT Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Inc. is an American multinational technology company specializing
in Internet-related services and products having successfully captured
the search engine market. The company has proved to have many different
strengths due to their successful. First off, Google’s Search Engine is
the most dominate search engine in the world, processing over 40,000
search queries every second on average. This translates to over 3.5
billion searches per day and 1.2 trillion searches per year worldwide.
Google Search leads this market for being asked 65.4% of questions.
Yahoo! Search comes in second with 15.3% queries, followed by Microsoft
Bing at 10.7%.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:60&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:60&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s Search feature is something that everyone can use because it is
so simple and straightforward. One search can lead to a million
different answers but Google can help one find exactly what they are
looking for. The Google brand recognition is so powerful that the term
“to Google” is even in the Dictionary. Everyone around the world knows
what Google is and what they do. When people need an answer to a
question, the first thing they think of is “to Google it” because they
know that whatever they are looking for will be just a few clicks
away.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:61&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:61&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;61&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google also has a strong organizational culture that is focused on
innovation, while providing quality of life to its employees. On their
company website, Google proudly displays videos of its offices and
employees at work. Each employee is encouraged to pursue innovative
ideas about his or her passions. This is demonstrated, for example,
through the spare time allotted to software engineers who are allowed to
spend 2 hours per day on their own projects of choice. Google believes
that fostering employee creativity and a casual environment that
provides a quality of life is the best way to attract and maintain
quality employees. This policy has been successful as employment at
Google is highly selective and desirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the Google organizational culture effectively translates
into its innovative products. Google has been ranked No.1 in Fortune’s
latest annual list of “100 Best Companies to Work For.” The search
engine giant employs 18,500 people in the United States alone and is the
most sought after employer in the world. Google has an innovative and
creative culture where they promote employee well being and imagination.
This company is great to work for having very low employee turnover
rates by offering high salaries and good benefits to staff that will
raise the company’s productivity.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:62&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:62&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;62&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company extended its locations abroad to locations such as Canada,
Mexico, United Kingdom, South Korea, Taiwan, Puerto Rico, and
Australia.  Its expansion has increased the numbers of members and this
directly connected to the increase of profit. Google offers high quality
products and services at low prices and they don’t sell many products.
These factors lead to consumer loyalty in the long run. Google also has
a strong financial performance which helps the company maintain its
stand in the market and build the shareholders’ confidence.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:63&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:63&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;63&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has a broad range of services such as online advertising, online
display ads, and mobile advertising. It also offers various platforms
and applications including: Google Apps, Google Buzz, Google Book
Search, Google Checkout, Google News, Google Chrome, Google Play, Google
TV, and Google Wave. The company’s future business initiatives include
Google Editions and Google Android Market. The product portfolio of the
company also include: Gmail, Web Search, Toolbar, Custom Search Engines,
Maps, YouTube, Google Image Search, Google Scholar, Google Base, Google
Finance, Search Google Co-op, Custom Search, Google Video, Google Docs,
Google Spreadsheets, Google Slides, Google Calendar, Google Desktop,
Google Pack, Google Earth, Google Sketchup and Sketchup Pro, Google
Mobile, Google Labs, Google AdWords, Google AdSense, and Android. The
pro of having all these products is that they are completely integrated
with each other and work well combined together.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:64&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:64&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is the largest and most favored search engine. It is difficult to
locate it’s weaknesses compared to their competitors because it is the
most extensive search engine available on the Web. Google’s capabilities
are constantly evolving to accommodate the needs of users. Google’s
existence completely relies on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a lack of advertisement can be a barrier for the company
to attract more customers. Google does little in the advertising
department because they are such a well known brand that they don’t need
advertisement, however they should keep their name relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has been involved in many patent and litigation disputes with
other companies over the years that have tarnished their reputation.
Google has also been experiencing failing ad rates. In recent years,
especially 2013, the company has been faced with declining revenues from
ads and as a result, the profitability of the company has taken a hit.
Also, many spammers manipulate Google’s ranking technology by creating
dummy sites with thousands of links to pages that they wanted Google to
rank highly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Google is so successful they could still be open to more
opportunities. Google’s social networking could use many improvements.
Google + reportedly beat out Twitter with 359 million users but is still
far behind Facebooks 701 million users. Social networking is a hard
market to enter into, therefore Google + is still struggling to gain
attention and users. Google + is not taken seriously as a social
networking site because Facebook is still the one to beat.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:65&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:65&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smartphone market in the U.S. isn’t saturated yet and millions still
need smartphones, many of which will come with Android’s OS. Many people
are against Apple products which leaves a whole market open for Google
smartphones. Currently, Google has Android and Nexus smartphones but are
not saturating the market how they should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Google Ventures is a relatively new capital venture group within
Google. Their main focus is investments in companies that are developing
new and potentially world-changing technologies. At present, Google
Ventures only considers investing in start-up firms within North
America. Google has already launched a few new models of notebooks,
tablets, and smartphones into the market but these were only
introduction models. Google could strengthen its entry into the
electronic device industry by introducing more products for more
customer groups and cut out its market share. This would result in
tighter integration of its software products and diversified income.
Google acquisitions and mergers are highly important to the company.
Google purchased Motorola in 2011, allowing the company to generate
revenue from the sale of hardware and services in both the mobile and
home segments. Google’s new products include: Google Glasses, electronic
cars, tablets, and Google TV. Google is such a powerfully well known
brand that is completely in control of the market but they still have
many opportunities. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:66&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:66&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;66&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is an important company, however that doesn’t deter them from
having many threats. Because the company offers a wide range of products
and services, it has a lot of competitors such as retail supermarkets,
wholesale stores, gas station, insurance companies, and so on. Since
this monopolistic competition can attract potential competitors easily,
the company can have hard time by dealing with this issue. Google is
involved in numerous markets that are highly competitive. Competition
could intensify with the entry of new competitors, development of new
technologies, products and services, and convergence. The company
witnesses competition from general purpose search engines including
Yahoo and Microsoft’s Bing as well as social networks such as Facebook
and Twitter. Google also faces many threats in regards to security and
privacy issues. This has been a problem for Google who has been
struggling to strengthen security measures to prevent outside parties
from breaching the company. Google has a lot of important and fragile
customer information that would cause a lot of problems if it was
breached.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:67&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:67&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;67&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strategies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are many different ways you can use our services – to search for
and share information, to communicate with other people or to create new
content. When you share information with us, for example by creating a
Google Account, we can make those services even better – to show you
more relevant search results and ads, to help you connect with people or
to make sharing with others quicker and easier. As you use our services,
we want you to be clear how we’re using information and the ways in
which you can protect your privacy.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:68&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:68&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;68&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is the opening statement from Google’s Privacy Policy regarding
the utilization of private information collected from its users. If a
user adheres to the policy, Google maintains the right to collect a wide
range of data from the various service-platforms it offers. The truth of
the matter is that all users of the Internet have different privacy
concerns. Therefore, in Google’s opening statement, the firm tries to
reassure the end-user by stating that all private information will be
used to enhance their overall Google experience. Private information can
be defined as any number or letter that spells out or represents any
demographic detail of a person. Moreover, Google treats its end-users
private data with much care, although it’s not Google who the people are
afraid of. The people are ultimately in fear of the government tapping
into our private lives. Therefore, it is critical that Google implements
new strategies to prevent government infiltration, while introducing new
ways of making its practices using private data increasingly transparent
to end-users.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:69&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:69&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When implementing a business-level or Corporate-level strategy, no
matter what, it is important to build off of the firm’s
core-competencies. The core-competencies that are found within Google
Inc. are software engineering, content indexing, maintaining scalable
hardware infrastructure, and the company’s culture of innovation should
be considered too. These principles followed by Google have allowed them
to create a solid line of core products, which include, PageRank,
Indexing Technology, Google Ads, and the Google mapping platform. The
resources demanded from these products require private information from
end-users that exposes their geographic and demographic data.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:70&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:70&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;70&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quality that is working largely with, but also against Google, is the
fact of how “geeky” they are. The algorithms and different engineering
techniques that it takes for Google to exist seems to make it hard for
them to articulate how the end-user’s information is being used,
captured, and stored. The first suggestion would to be to utilize the
“Google Privacy” channel on YouTube more efficiently. Currently, the
Google controlled channel has only 40,000 subscribers and posts only an
average of two times a year.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:71&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:71&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;71&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The channel isn’t doing a very good
job of making end-users conscious of its privacy practices. The firm
could do a better job of making end-users aware of their practices by
introducing an interactive video every quarter demonstrating exactly
what they take from you and how they will utilize it to produce an
improved overall experience. Users should be forced to watch the video
as they are forced to watch an ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way of providing transparency within their privacy practices
would be by utilizing their software-engineering abilities. In order to
truly provide a solution toward these privacy concerns, Google first
needs to know what the end-users’ main concerns are regarding personal
information. In order to gain a better understanding of what is
concerning these users, it would be appropriate to incorporate a
semiannually poll that all registered users must participate within.
This will provide a channel of communication between the end-users and
Google, allowing them to focus in on the issues of privacy. Google and
firms alike cannot only assume what its users are thinking – they must
give their users a voice. It is important that Google has the ability to
receive feedback, which will ultimately help sustain the firm in such an
evolving environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final suggestion of implementation this analysis encourages the most
will offer is the option of “Google blackout.” Blackout searching is a
quick accessible feature on Google.com that offers registered and
unregistered users the option of completely anonymous web searching. The
blackout feature will prevent data from being collected through its
end-users on all of Google’s platforms. Google has brand equity large
enough to afford the backfire from this implementation. If users choose
the option to use Google Blackout, they may not notice any differences,
but some users will notice a big difference from within their search
results. The people who notice a difference are experiencing this
because by being completely anonymous, Google loses the ability to
identify you. If Google looses the ability to identify you, the user
will experience search results on a broader level than what they are
used to. Therefore, this will either allow the end-user to understand
the importance of Google’s privacy practices by experiencing the
significant changes in search results, or it will simply give the people
what they want, anonymity. The means of implementation of this strategy
largely depends on their software engineering team. The team would have
to develop a separate platform that is accessible within Google.com.
This platform would be engineered almost identically to its originator,
although it wouldn’t include the various methods of personalization used
to improve search results. The idea behind all of this is to help
end-users realize the value of the firm’s privacy practices through
helping them realize that sharing their private information is worth
having the most effective Google experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Works Cited&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/history-sergey-brin-larry-page-and-google-strategy-2011-3&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.businessinsider.com/history-sergey-brin-larry-page-and-google-strategy-2011-3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtube&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.3414189,-71.2457625,15z&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.3414189,-71.2457625,15z&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bi.galegroup.com/essentials/article/GALE%7CI2501312700/c0bf76ecd0964520149cc15cf1a59771?u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://bi.galegroup.com/essentials/article/GALE%7CI2501312700/c0bf76ecd0964520149cc15cf1a59771?u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Groups&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Groups&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Latitude&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Latitude&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube_Next_Lab_and_Audience_Development_Group&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube_Next_Lab_and_Audience_Development_Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases. Mason, OH:
Cengage Learning. p. 31 -42&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://searchsoa.techtarget.com/definition/Gmail&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://searchsoa.techtarget.com/definition/Gmail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.google.com/marketplace/?pann=gam&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://apps.google.com/marketplace/?pann=gam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eruptingmind.com/the-business-environment-and-its-effects-on-google/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.eruptingmind.com/the-business-environment-and-its-effects-on-google/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://panmore.com/google-pestel-pestle-analysis-recommendations&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://panmore.com/google-pestel-pestle-analysis-recommendations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technology-essays.com/essays/bells_post_industrial_society_essay.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.technology-essays.com/essays/bells_post_industrial_society_essay.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp#ixzz3qkU3R0Em&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp#ixzz3qkU3R0Em&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexa.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.alexa.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2014/11/17/top-10-research-development/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://fortune.com/2014/11/17/top-10-research-development/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/co?s=GOOG+Competitors&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/co?s=GOOG+Competitors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netmarketshare.com/search-engine-market-share.aspx?qprid=4&amp;amp;qpcustomd=0&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.netmarketshare.com/search-engine-market-share.aspx?qprid=4&amp;amp;qpcustomd=0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/investor/reports/ar14/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/investor/reports/ar14/index.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://files.shareholder.com/downloads/YHOO/967709701x0x826745/b7e0b2eb-68d3-4612-9307-03478b206a37/YahooInc2014AnnualReport.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://files.shareholder.com/downloads/YHOO/967709701x0x826745/b7e0b2eb-68d3-4612-9307-03478b206a37/YahooInc2014AnnualReport.pdf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.google.com/financial/tables.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://investor.google.com/financial/tables.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/internal-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/internal-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/is?s=GOOG+Income+Statement&amp;amp;annual&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/is?s=GOOG+Income+Statement&amp;amp;annual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.google.com/pdf/20141231_google_10K.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://investor.google.com/pdf/20141231_google_10K.pdf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/bs?s=GOOG+Balance+Sheet&amp;amp;annual&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/bs?s=GOOG+Balance+Sheet&amp;amp;annual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgGXuHUW4CE&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgGXuHUW4CE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/business/analysing-the-core-competencies-of-google-inc-business-essay.php#ixzz3qpdYFnxK&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/business/analysing-the-core-competencies-of-google-inc-business-essay.php#ixzz3qpdYFnxK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/googleprivacy/about&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/googleprivacy/about&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stonybrook.digication.com/calvins_google/Welcome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://stonybrook.digication.com/calvins_google/Welcome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;\
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-%09threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-
threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;\
&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003p%09rodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;co%09ntentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=%09las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003p
rodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;co
ntentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=
las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/history-sergey-brin-larry-page-and-google-strategy-2011-3&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.businessinsider.com/history-sergey-brin-larry-page-and-google-strategy-2011-3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Google.com &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/history/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAyUNI3_V2c&amp;amp;feature=youtube&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.3414189,-71.2457625,15z&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/maps/@42.3414189,-71.2457625,15z&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.landley.net/history/mirror/net/google-history.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:13&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/about/company/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/about/company/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:13&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:14&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bi.galegroup.com/essentials/article/GALE%7CI2501312700/c0bf76ecd0964520149cc15cf1a59771?u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://bi.galegroup.com/essentials/article/GALE%7CI2501312700/c0bf76ecd0964520149cc15cf1a59771?u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:14&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:15&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:16&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Groups&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Groups&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:16&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:17&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:17&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:18&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodgeball_(service)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:18&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:19&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Latitude&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Latitude&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:19&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:21&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube_Next_Lab_and_Audience_Development_Group&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube_Next_Lab_and_Audience_Development_Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:21&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:22&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning. p. 31 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:22&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:23&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning. p. 32 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:23&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:24&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:24&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:25&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://searchsoa.techtarget.com/definition/Gmail&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://searchsoa.techtarget.com/definition/Gmail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:25&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:26&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:26&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:27&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning. p. 32 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:27&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:28&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/googleapps/googleapps_overview.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:28&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:29&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:29&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:30&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.google.com/marketplace/?pann=gam&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://apps.google.com/marketplace/?pann=gam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:30&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:31&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:31&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:32&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning. p. 40 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:32&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:33&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:33&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:34&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:34&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:35&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eruptingmind.com/the-business-environment-and-its-effects-on-google/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.eruptingmind.com/the-business-environment-and-its-effects-on-google/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:35&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:36&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:36&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:37&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:37&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:38&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:38&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:39&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:39&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:40&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:40&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:41&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.academia.edu/5356952/A_Case_Study_of_Google_Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:41&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:42&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://panmore.com/google-pestel-pestle-analysis-recommendations&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://panmore.com/google-pestel-pestle-analysis-recommendations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:42&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:43&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/external-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:43&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:44&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:44&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:45&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technology-essays.com/essays/bells_post_industrial_society_essay.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.technology-essays.com/essays/bells_post_industrial_society_essay.htm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:45&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:46&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp#ixzz3qkU3R0Em&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp#ixzz3qkU3R0Em&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:46&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:47&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexa.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.alexa.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:47&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:48&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hitt/Ireland/Hoskisson. (2015). Strategic Management Cases.
Mason, OH: Cengage Learning &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:48&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:49&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2014/11/17/top-10-research-development/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://fortune.com/2014/11/17/top-10-research-development/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:49&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:50&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/071515/search-engines-compete-google.asp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:50&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:51&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/co?s=GOOG+Competitors&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/co?s=GOOG+Competitors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:51&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:52&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netmarketshare.com/search-engine-market-share.aspx?qprid=4&amp;amp;qpcustomd=0&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.netmarketshare.com/search-engine-market-share.aspx?qprid=4&amp;amp;qpcustomd=0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:52&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:53&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/investor/reports/ar14/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/investor/reports/ar14/index.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:53&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:54&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://files.shareholder.com/downloads/YHOO/967709701x0x826745/b7e0b2eb-68d3-4612-9307-03478b206a37/YahooInc2014AnnualReport.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://files.shareholder.com/downloads/YHOO/967709701x0x826745/b7e0b2eb-68d3-4612-9307-03478b206a37/YahooInc2014AnnualReport.pdf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:54&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:55&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.google.com/financial/tables.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://investor.google.com/financial/tables.html&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:55&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:56&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benmorrow.info/blog/internal-analysis-of-google-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://benmorrow.info/blog/internal-analysis-of-google-inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:56&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:57&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/is?s=GOOG+Income+Statement&amp;amp;annual&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/is?s=GOOG+Income+Statement&amp;amp;annual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:57&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:58&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.google.com/pdf/20141231_google_10K.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://investor.google.com/pdf/20141231_google_10K.pdf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:58&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:59&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/bs?s=GOOG+Balance+Sheet&amp;amp;annual&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://finance.yahoo.com/q/bs?s=GOOG+Balance+Sheet&amp;amp;annual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:59&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:60&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:60&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:61&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:61&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:62&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stonybrook.digication.com/calvins_google/Welcome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://stonybrook.digication.com/calvins_google/Welcome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:62&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:63&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:63&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:64&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:64&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:65&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:65&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:66&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/information-technology/the-strength-weakness-opportunities-and-threats-analysis-information-technology-essay.php&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:66&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:67&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://go.galegroup.com/ps/retrieve.do?sort=RELEVANCE&amp;amp;docType=Company+overview&amp;amp;tabID=T003&amp;amp;prodId=GVRL&amp;amp;searchId=R2&amp;amp;resultListType=RESULT_LIST&amp;amp;searchType=AdvancedSearchForm&amp;amp;contentSegment=&amp;amp;currentPosition=1&amp;amp;searchResultsType=MultiTab&amp;amp;inPS=true&amp;amp;userGroupName=las&amp;amp;docId=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;contentSet=GALE%7CCX2979600110&amp;amp;authCount=1&amp;amp;u=las&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:67&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:68&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:68&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:69&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgGXuHUW4CE&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgGXuHUW4CE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:69&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:70&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/business/analysing-the-core-competencies-of-google-inc-business-essay.php#ixzz3qpdYFnxK&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.ukessays.com/essays/business/analysing-the-core-competencies-of-google-inc-business-essay.php#ixzz3qpdYFnxK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:70&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:71&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/googleprivacy/about&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/googleprivacy/about&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:71&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
<category term="Google" />
<category term="Case study" />
<summary></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>REVITALIZATION THROUGH INNOVATION: LASELL STUDENTS TRAVEL TO DETROIT, LEARN FROM ENTREPRENEURS REBUILDING MOTOR CITY</title>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/opportunity-detroit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="REVITALIZATION THROUGH INNOVATION: LASELL STUDENTS TRAVEL TO DETROIT, LEARN FROM ENTREPRENEURS REBUILDING MOTOR CITY" />
<published>2016-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
<updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/opportunity-detroit</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/opportunity-detroit">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/OD/OD_Logo-compressor.png&quot; alt=&quot;opportunity_detroit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;revitalization-through-innovation-lasell-students-travel-to-detroit-learn-from-entrepreneurs-rebuilding-motor-city&quot;&gt;REVITALIZATION THROUGH INNOVATION: LASELL STUDENTS TRAVEL TO DETROIT, LEARN FROM ENTREPRENEURS REBUILDING MOTOR CITY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harris Demos, &lt;a href=&quot;http://linkedin.com/in/manifestlife&quot;&gt;Isaiah King&lt;/a&gt;, Alexa Katsigianis(BUSS337 Managing the Growing Company)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our small group of &lt;a href=&quot;http:lasell.edu&quot;&gt;Lasell College&lt;/a&gt; students took our first few steps
through the Detroit Metro Airport, our opinions immediately began to
shift our perceived image of the “broken city” of Michigan. Our vision
based on previous hearsay. However, Lasell College is aware that
students are more successful when they can connect their learning
experiences from the classroom into the real world. The connected
learning philosophy and application has opened our minds to exploring
opportunity of the unknown, which Detroit proved to be the best
“unknown” any of us could have pictured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/OD/OD_Dog-compressor.png&quot; alt=&quot;opportunity_detroit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/OD/OD_Piano-compressor.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The streets showed us vivacious colors and innovative ideas that many other
United States cities do not. Detroit’s vision is to transform Downtown into an
urban neighborhood with a unique point of view, which is exactly what is being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through these alterations, Detroit will continue to attract a young
demographic: one that is willing to jump at the first site of
opportunity. These simple yet brilliant creations proved to us, and will
prove to the incoming urban population, that government officials have
the desire to implement change. This refreshing outlook with
open-mindedness has not always been persistent in the past. However,
higher interest and connections from Detroit residents are beginning to
transform and re-populate the downtown. This will continue to bring
fresh business ideas into the thriving city of Detroit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detroit is one of America’s greatest cities and is known for its
historical development and success within the early stages of the
automotive industry. Ford Motor Company was founded in 1903 by an
entrepreneur named Henry Ford. Even though Ford did not create the first
automobile, he did develop and manufacture the first automobile that
many middle class Americans could afford. The Dodge brothers, Walter
Chrysler, and other automotive pioneers paved a road that allowed
Detroit to become the global automotive capital. In the year 1950, there
were almost 300,000 manufacturing jobs but that number dwindled down to
less than 27,000 in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1960 Detroit had the highest income per person in each household but
in 2013, the city ranked 35^th^ out of 50 states. From 1960 to 2013, the
city slowly lost over fifty percent of its population and filed for
Section 9 bankruptcy. Detroit went from the fourth biggest city in the
United States down to the 18^th^. It is apparent that Detroit was once a
place flourishing with opportunity that allowed its residents to clearly
vision and achieve the “American Dream”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Currently opportunities do
exist, possibly even more than before, but these opportunities were
manifested from the rundown ecosystem Detroit has rebirthed into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, Detroit is the largest city to ever go bankrupt. This
economic tragedy was precisely four times larger than Jefferson County,
Alabama’s $4 billion filing in 2011. The reason for Detroit’s
bankruptcy mostly involves the word “fiscal”, which refers to economics
from the perspective of the system to which they belong – with the
central factors including taxes and spending. More specific reasoning
for the cause comes from the widespread corruption within Detroit
municipalities which resulted in a billion-dollar “borrowing binge”.
Detroit was caught up in borrowing unreasonable amounts of money for
cash-flow reasons but failed to replace the cost of these investments.
The culture of the fiscal economy in Detroit made a shift in the late
20^th^ century. This involved spending future money for purchases that
were needed presently. The city was able to function temporarily but
filed for bankruptcy in 2013 with an accumulated amount of $20 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detroit has its obstacles to overcome the economic downfall. The city
developed a reputation of lacking fiscal responsibility. One of the most
obvious outcomes of the bankruptcy was unemployment. The economic
structure of the city was built upon large automobile companies. When
downtown went bankrupt, people were dislocated from their jobs and homes
due to the large business owners’ outsourcing human capital. The
residents flocked the city due to the economic downturn beginning in
1947.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between 1947 and 1978 there were 1.36 million jobs lost within the
automotive industry in the United States due to the importation of
Japanese manufacturing. The city population dropped forty percent from
1970 to 2006, and as of 2013 the total population was less than 700,000
people. These large corporations did not utilize the opportunities for
hiring within the community or even the country, which could have
prevented the bankruptcy all together. Instead, Detroit residents had
poorer economic standings due to the over-production of cars&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were not in the financial position to make major investments such
as buying a new car every few years, and as a result the demand for cars
was significantly lower than their supply. Once the big businesses in a
given area went bankrupt, such as General Motors and other large
automobile companies in Detroit, they were no longer able to pay taxes
and therefore provide for public services. The lack of input and output
of money into the economy at the time of bankruptcy negatively impacted
other local businesses, such as schools and public transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This caused a large amount of blight throughout the city. As of 2013,
nearly one in four buildings in Detroit are abandoned or on the verge of
becoming owned by the state in order to be demolished&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This lack of
occupancy makes it difficult for Detroit to attract young professionals
into the city. Buildings being destroyed and rebuilt will take time.
Therefore it is imperative that Detroit turns these buildings into
something that can be used instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the economic strain on our national fiscal system, it is not
uncommon for bankruptcy to negatively impact a wide range of people,
including individuals, communities, and businesses of all sizes, both
local and corporate. All in all, the fiscal policies of Detroit were
ineffective and there were numerous reasons that lead to its economic
failure. The Downtown Detroit Project is taking steps to reduce and
possibly eliminate these threats of urban decay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building an Entrepreneurial Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through these economic struggles, Detroit has managed to begin piecing
together the puzzle the recession left. As the pieces fell into place,
something unimaginable began to appear: an entrepreneurial ecosystem. A
world of businesses formed, both start-up and matured, run by the people
who own or wish to be part of these businesses began to emerge.
Unfortunately as we all know, it is not always easy to provide capital
or enough creative ideas to innovate the mangled city, but that did not
stop a man that embodies entrepreneurial spirit; Daniel Gilbert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/OD/OD_Dan_Gilbert-compressor.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dan_Gilbert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known as the savior of Detroit,[Gilbert](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan_Gilbert_(businessman) has gone above and beyond with aiding the city in its time of need. Gilbert, a Detroit Native,
dedicated large amounts of his time, efforts, and capital to help his
city rise after seeing it fall. A major contributing factor in Gilbert’s
investments in the city is his love for business. At a young age Gilbert
was captivated by business and knew that it was the life for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This life does not come easy, and Gilbert knew an opportunity would not
just fall into his lap. Gilbert worked hard and now currently serves as
the founder and chairman of both Quicken Loans and Rock Ventures.
Quicken Loans is the nation’s second largest mortgage lender and Rock
Ventures has over 110 partnering companies. These major companies began
to see the light of day in 2010 when Dan Gilbert initiated his big move
to the city of Detroit. Gilbert managed to move 1,200 team members of
Quicken Loans to Michigan in a record amount of time. Once these team
members flooded the city, the expansion of his empire throughout
downtown Detroit began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From investing roughly $1.3 billion in real estate, Gilbert owned and
renovated nearly 60 properties in the inner city limits. This gave his
new Detroit team a professional “playground” to work with. This
playground consists of offices where space is utilized in a creative way
and team members can come together, regardless of position in the
company, and collaborate about innovative ideas&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a playground sounds fun and exciting, creating it to be a
positive work environment proved to be a challenge. Coming to a city of
despair can be overwhelming for many non-residents. For Gilbert, on the
other hand, this is an obstacle that can be overcome. If Governor Rick
Snyder can confidently state Dan Gilbert “has a track record as a
successful entrepreneur and innovator” due to the amount of progress
that has already been made&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. With the vision to synthesize a more
stimulating city, the goal was to attract young and well-educated
entrepreneurs. A cheap yet inspiring city that has an edgy and original
tone is the perfect environment for these newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reputation of the city, however, makes it difficult for newcomers to
consider Detroit as a livable work environment. The image of the city is
crucial to have an inviting feel. Blight is a major contributing factor
as to why foreigners do not feel safe. Blight is defined as abandoned
and rundown buildings. Detroit created a special task force to
reconstruct the city. As each condemned and abandoned building gets
updated, it’s one step closer to transforming Detroit into an
entrepreneurial utopia&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this utopia created was no accident. The Quicken Loans office
showcases a full model scaled replica of the city. Each building or
property is lit up as Gilbert purchase it. Detroit went from having 48
of the city’s largest office spaces unoccupied to having only 17
remaining unused. Also with employment boosting from 78,000-85,000 in
only 4 years, there is much to be done to prepare the city for the
number of residents that will follow those who have already joined this
business renaissance movement&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a Detroit resident is not about just living in the city anymore,
it is about being part of the entrepreneurial experience and lifestyle.
Needing approximately $45,000 annually to live comfortably in Detroit,
the average cost of living is far lower than other major American
cities&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. New college graduates will come for the low cost of living
but stay for the experiences. From the Cavaliers inspired basketball
court within the Quicken Loans headquarters to the colorful office
spaces, one will feel astonished yet instantly comfortable with the work
environment and culture. Each team member that is added becomes a link
in the chain, which makes the city stronger. The opportunities in
Detroit are endless and due to the efforts Gilbert and many other
for-profit and non-profit companies, the most compelling being
Opportunity Detroit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opportunity Detroit is a non-profit organization that promotes the
awareness of Detroit’s story. It shows potential Detroit customers or
businesses what the city has experienced in the past and how these
lessons have impacted their future growth. The umbrella company under
Rock Venture also publicizes the government officials and investors’
plan for downtown. Placing extreme importance on resident feedback,
Opportunity Detroit’s vision is to provide Detroit residents with a city
that is innovative and useful that agrees with their everyday lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan to revitalize the city has been
portioned into six major sections of the city:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/OD/OD_Map-compressor.png&quot; alt=&quot;OD_Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These six sections each have specific implementation plans in order to
achieve the final goal for Detroit, centralized around one main vision;
the transformation of Woodward Ave. into a “promenade” street. The
promenade feel (“to walk” translated from French), simply means Detroit
officials want to provide the citizens with a relaxing environment that
will entertain them as they walk the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest factor Opportunity Detroit is considering when marketing to
their target is the modification of the streets. The addition of
sidewalk activation crossing signals and the M1-rail system will promote
a highly-valued pedestrian environment. Encouraging Detroit citizens to
walk in the city will turn them into potential customers of the young
businesses that are currently thriving. Integrating food and beverage,
entertainment, and retail shopping needs into the everyday lives of the
citizens will give them a connection to the city as well. As the
citizens continue connecting to the “Detroit pride” that not only
radiates through the current residents, but through the promotion
efforts of Opportunity Detroit, more people will begin to leave the
outskirts and flock into the bustling city&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shift in lifestyle coincides with Opportunity Detroit’s most
important factor to consider: recognize potential resident locations,
build them to acceptable living conditions and fill them with residents.
Capitalizing on the real estate market during this time is essential for
Detroit to become profitable. As the city begins to repopulate with
Michigan residents, more people will come from other parts of the
country to offer their ideas and continue to bring opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change can often be tricky to implement if not done correctly. However
officials’ stress on “placemaking” ensures customer satisfaction.
Essentially, placemaking gives citizens the opportunity to give feedback
to officials in order to ensure that all of the modifications that are
being achieved are accepted by the public. Giving residents the ability
to comment during the process will ensure that spaces are provided to
them that are easily accessible, engaging, comfortable and welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the previously successful implementations already in place,
Detroit has every opportunity to succeed. It has history; Detroit is the
largest and most recent city to declare bankruptcy in the United States
to date. However, they have learned valuable lessons from their failures
which gave them the capability to better execute their future vision for
Detroit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opportunity Detroit’s promotion is a key factor in order for investors
and official’s efforts to be seen. As the education of what is happening
now in Detroit increases, people will begin to flock to this once
“broken” city and transform it into its true potential: a unique and
incredible opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Works Cited

A Better Solution for Detroit&#39;s Blight. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12,
2014, from

http://www.thefiscaltimes.com/Articles/2014/05/30/Better-Solution-Detroit-s-Blight

About Us. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12, 2014, from
http://opportunitydetroit.com/about-us/

Auto industry decline, racial tension at the root of Detroit&#39;s collapse.
(n.d.). Retrieved November

12, 2014, from

http://www.pennlive.com/midstate/index.ssf/201

&quot;Choose Thinking: A Blog by Dan Gilbert.&quot; *About Dan Gilbert*. N.p.,
n.d. Web. 25 Nov. 2014.

&quot;Dan Gilbert.&quot; *Chairman and Founder, Quicken Loans Inc. • Majority
Owner, Cleveland *

*Cavaliers*. N.p., n.d. Web. 25 Nov. 2014.

Gilbert, D. (2014, November 7). Choose Thinking: A Blog by Dan Gilbert.
Retrieved November

12, 2014,

from http://choosethinking.com/

&quot;Gilbertville: A Billionaire&#39;s Drive To Rebuild The Motor City.&quot;
*Forbes*. Forbes Magazine, n.d.

Web. 25 Nov. 2014.

United States Census Bureau. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12, 2014, from

http://quickfacts.census.gov/qfd/states/26/2622000.html --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REVITALIZATION THROUGH INNOVATION: LASELL STUDENTS TRAVEL TO DETROIT,
LEARN FROM ENTREPRENEURS REBUILDING MOTOR CITY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Auto industry decline, racial tension at the root of Detroit’s
collapse. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12, 2014, from&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;http://www.pennlive.com/midstate/index.ssf/201 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;United States Census Bureau. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12, 2014,
from http://quickfacts.census.gov/qfd/states/26/2622000.html &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A Better Solution for Detroit’s Blight. (n.d.). Retrieved November
12, 2014, from&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;http://www.thefiscaltimes.com/Articles/2014/05/30/Better-Solution-Detroit-s-Blight &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Choose Thinking: A Blog by Dan Gilbert.” &lt;em&gt;About Dan Gilbert&lt;/em&gt;.
N.p., n.d. Web. 25 Nov. 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Dan Gilbert.” &lt;em&gt;Chairman and Founder, Quicken Loans Inc. •
Majority Owner, Cleveland Cavaliers&lt;/em&gt;. N.p., n.d. Web. 25 Nov. 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Gilbertville: A Billionaire’s Drive To Rebuild The Motor City.”
&lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;. Forbes Magazine, n.d. Web. 25 Nov. 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sorge, Marge. &lt;em&gt;Detroit Facts Economic Development Final 8-15-13&lt;/em&gt;
(n.d.): n. pag. Web. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Cost of Living Comparison:Detroit, Michigan - Boston,
Massachusetts.” &lt;em&gt;Cost of Living Comparison: Compare Detroit,
Michigan to Boston, Massachusetts&lt;/em&gt;. N.p., n.d. Web. 09 Dec. 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;About Us. (n.d.). Retrieved November 12, 2014, from
http://opportunitydetroit.com/about-us/ &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
<category term="Opportunity" />
<category term="Detroit" />
<category term="Entrepreneur" />
<summary></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Isaiah King - Social Entrepreneur</title>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Isaiah King - Social Entrepreneur" />
<published>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
<updated>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Isaiah-Social-Entrepreneurship</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/blog/">&lt;p&gt;There was once a time where I was totally opposed toward the idea of college,
and school in general. My first year at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lasell.edu&quot;&gt;Lasell&lt;/a&gt; was especially tough because I
spent two semesters on conduct probation. This left me with a feeling that
overwhelmingly weighed down on my shoulders. When I received the letter saying I
was being suspended, I felt like I broke my mother’s heart. I appealed the
decision and thankfully, I was invited to come back after promising improvement.
My seemingly one and only chance to redeem my college education didn’t go as
planned. I earned a embarrassing 1.7 GPA the following semester, which put me
back on the brink of getting suspended again. The second suspension letter came
right before Christmas and couldn’t believe that I’ve once again put my Mother
through this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All throughout my life my mother has been my main support system and the person
who’s always influenced me the most. This amazing woman had me when she was 18,
we truly grew up together. Her main goal in life was to provide me with something
she never had the chance to experience, earning a degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the second letter came, I was absolutely ready to drop out of college. I
persuaded myself into thinking that I was over the fact that I had let my Mother
completely down. That thought led to other thoughts, which ended up helping me
realize why I wasn’t succeeding. I came to the realization that I wasn’t attending
college for the betterment of myself, but instead I was there to fulfill the
happiness of the one person who has always been there for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent a second appeal letter as soon as I realized what was potentially wrong
in order to give my self a true chance as a college student. I was able to appeal
suspension again with success that felt mighty shameful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of winter break, I really tried finding out who I actually was.
Fortunately, I was able to manifest a route that allowed me to excel as a student
and as an individual. Choosing to continue my education by studying entrepreneurship
was the best decision of my life and now, I’m trying to build off of that. I’ve
met so many amazing people with beautiful mindsets.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="Isaiah" />
<category term="King" />
<category term="Social" />
<category term="Entrepreneur" />
<summary>There was once a time where I was totally opposed toward the idea of college,and school in general. My first year at Lasell was especially tough because Ispent two semesters on conduct probation. This left me with a feeling thatoverwhelmingly weighed down on my shoulders. When I received the letter saying Iwas being suspended, I felt like I broke my mother’s heart. I appealed thedecision and thankfully, I was invited to come back after promising improvement.My seemingly one and only chance to redeem my college education didn’t go asplanned. I earned a embarrassing 1.7 GPA the following semester, which put meback on the brink of getting suspended again. The second suspension letter cameright before Christmas and couldn’t believe that I’ve once again put my Motherthrough this.</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
