<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-04-26T18:02:13-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/</id>
<title>Manifest Life</title>
<entry>
<title>Isaiah King - Student Entrepreneur</title>
<link href="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Isaiah-Student-Entrepreneurship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Isaiah King - Student Entrepreneur" />
<published>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
<updated>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
<id>http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Isaiah-Student-Entrepreneurship</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://manifestlifeinc.github.io/Isaiah-Student-Entrepreneurship/">&lt;p&gt;There was once a time where I was totally opposed toward the idea of college,
and school in general. My first year at [Lasell][http://lasell.edu] was especially tough because I
spent two semesters on conduct probation. This left me with a feeling that
overwhelmingly weighed down on my shoulders. When I received the letter saying I
was being suspended, I felt like I broke my mother’s heart. I appealed the
decision and thankfully, I was invited to come back after promising improvement.
My seemingly one and only chance to redeem my college education didn’t go as
planned. I earned a embarrassing 1.7 GPA the following semester, which put me
back on the brink of getting suspended again. The second suspension letter came
right before Christmas and couldn’t believe that I’ve once again put my Mother
through this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All throughout my life my mother has been my main support system and the person
who’s always influenced me the most. This amazing woman had me when she was 18,
we truly grew up together. Her main goal in life was to provide me with something
she never had the chance to experience, earning a degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the second letter came, I was absolutely ready to drop out of college. I
persuaded myself into thinking that I was over the fact that I had let my Mother
completely down. That thought led to other thoughts, which ended up helping me
realize why I wasn’t succeeding. I came to the realization that I wasn’t attending
college for the betterment of myself, but instead I was there to fulfill the
happiness of the one person who has always been there for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent a second appeal letter as soon as I realized what was potentially wrong
in order to give my self a true chance as a college student. I was able to appeal
suspension again with success that felt mighty shameful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of winter break, I really tried finding out who I actually was.
Fortunately, I was able to manifest a route that allowed me to excel as a student
and as an individual. Choosing to continue my education by studying entrepreneurship
was the best decision of my life and now, I’m trying to build off of that. I’ve
met so many amazing people with beautiful mindsets.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="Isaiah" />
<category term="Student" />
<category term="Entrepreneur" />
<summary>There was once a time where I was totally opposed toward the idea of college,and school in general. My first year at [Lasell][http://lasell.edu] was especially tough because Ispent two semesters on conduct probation. This left me with a feeling thatoverwhelmingly weighed down on my shoulders. When I received the letter saying Iwas being suspended, I felt like I broke my mother’s heart. I appealed thedecision and thankfully, I was invited to come back after promising improvement.My seemingly one and only chance to redeem my college education didn’t go asplanned. I earned a embarrassing 1.7 GPA the following semester, which put meback on the brink of getting suspended again. The second suspension letter cameright before Christmas and couldn’t believe that I’ve once again put my Motherthrough this.</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
